In early 1972, a probe known as Pioneer 10 was launched into space
1972 年初，一艘名为先驱者十号的探测器发射升空
on a mission to the largest planet in the Solar System.
它的目标是前往太阳系的最大行星
After millennia of speculation and wonder,
人类经过数千年的猜测与想象
humanity got its first close-up view of Jupiter.
首次得到近距离的木星影像
Accelerated by the immense gravity of the planet,
由于木星的巨大引力
Pioneer 10 was then catapulted into deep space,
先驱者10号之后被弹入深空
destined to leave the Solar System and roam the galaxy for billions of years.
最后离开太阳系，在银河系中流浪数十亿年
On the off-chance that this vestige of humanity
倘若这人类的遗迹
should one day be intercepted by an alien intelligence,
有一天被外星智慧拦截
it was affixed with a message.
它便传达了一种信息
A message designed to answer three central questions.
这种信息是三个核心问题的答案
[Carl Sagan] Where we are, when we are, and who we are.
我们存在于何处，我们存在于何时，以及我们是谁
More than half a century has now passed
现今，距离我们的第一位太空信使的发射
since the launch of our first galactic emissary,
已经过去了半个多世纪
and in that time, we've made numerous attempts to communicate with life beyond.
在这段时间里，我们无数次尝试与外星生命沟通
Either by attaching greeting cards to probes headed for interstellar space
要么在向星际发射的探测器上附上贺卡
or by targeting our cosmic neighbors with high-powered beams of light.
要么将高功率的光束射向我们的宇宙邻居
So far, humanity's been left on read, but that could change at any moment.
到目前为止，人类的消息一直石沉大海，但这种状况可能随时改变
As long as we keep making noise, there's always a chance we'll be heard.
只要我们一直发声，总有可能被听到
An exceedingly slim chance, as we'll see, but a non-zero chance nonetheless.
我们会发现这种概率非常渺茫，但总归不是不可能
Given the paradigm-shifting potential of contacting beings from another world,
鉴于与外星生命取得联系可能带来的颠覆性影响
it sure would be nice to know what exactly we've been telling them all these years.
我们当然很想知道这些年究竟给他们传达了怎样的信息
I mean, don't get me wrong,
别误会，我的意思是
"Where we are, when we are, and who we are",
所谓“我们在何处，我们在何时，我们是谁”
sounds really neat and all, but it's not exactly rich in detail.
听起来不错，但它并没有很多细节
So let's start with that plaque on Pioneer 10.
让我们从先驱者号上的那块镀金铝板开始说起
What does it say, and more importantly,
来试图弄清它传达了什么，以及更重要地
to whom should I direct my anger when the aliens arrive to harvest my bones?
如果外星人真来歼灭我们，应该找谁算账呢？
The idea to attach a nmessage to Pioneer 10
在先驱者10号上面附加一条信息的主意
was the brainchild of journalist and author Eric Burgess.
来自于记者兼作家埃里克·伯吉斯
Less than four months before the probe was scheduled to launch,
探测器发射的不到四个月前
Burgess approached famed astronomer and science communicator Carl Sagan,
伯吉斯联系了著名的天文学家和科技传播者卡尔·萨根
who, in turn, relayed the proposal to NASA.
也就是后来将这个提议递交给NASA的人
Sagan was given three weeks to devise the message,
萨根有三个星期的时间来设计内容
and with the help of his wife and artist Linda
在他的艺术家妻子琳达
as well as fellow astronomer Frank Drake,
以及天体物理学家弗兰克·德雷克的帮助下
they scrambled together a series of pictograms
他们将一系列图示文字拼起来
etched into a gold-laden plate of aluminum.
蚀刻在一块镀金的铝板上
In the words of Sagan...
用萨根的话来说...
Near the upper-left corner, we find a diagram of hydrogen,
在左上角，我们可以看到一个氢元素的图示
the simplest and most abundant element in the universe.
这是宇宙中最简单的也是最丰富的元素
One electron bound to a proton.
由一个电子与质子结合而成
More specifically, the diagram depicts a single atom of hydrogen
更确切地说，这个图示描绘了一个
transitioning from one energy state to another,
在不同的能级之间跃迁的氢原子
which is meant to be conveyed by this horizontal line here in the middle.
这一点用中间的这条水平线表示
This shift in energy is known as a hyperfine transition,
这种能量的变化被称为超精细跃迁
and it's accompanied by the emission of a radio wave.
该过程伴随着无线电波的发射
That radio wave has a very specific frequency
这种无线电波具有一种十分特殊的频率
that's so prominent across the universe that we've given it a name,
在宇宙中极为显著，因此我们专门给它了一个名字
the hydrogen line.
氢线
Something that beings of sufficient intelligence
如果某种造物具有足够的智力
to capture a drifting spacecraft
去捕获一架漂游的飞船
would no doubt be aware of as well.
当然也会了解这些
In human terms, it has a frequency of about 1420 megahertz
用人类的话语来说，它具有大概 1420 兆赫兹的频率
which means that each cycle of the wave has a period of about 0.7 nanoseconds
这意味着该波的周期约为 0.7 纳秒
and a corresponding length of roughly 21 centimeters.
与之对应的波长大概有 21 厘米
The recipients would obviously express their measurements
很显然，这些信息的接收者
using something other than nanoseconds and centimeters,
会使用一些不是纳秒或厘米的单位来度量事物
but what's important here is that they're measuring the same thing
但重点在于它们也在观测同样的事物
and that that thing never changes.
并且这种东西是恒常不变的
The duration of one wavecycle and the distance covered during that cycle
一个波的周期以及一个周期传递的长度
remains the same across the universe.
在整个宇宙中都是不变的
This allows us to establish a shared unit of both time and length.
这使得我们能够建立相同的时间和长度单位
We're basically telling the aliens to treat their measurement
这基本上是在告诉外星人
of the hyperfine transition of neutral hydrogen
将它们对中性氢原子的超精细跃迁的度量
as one unit of time and one unit of length.
作为一单位的时间和一单位的长度
That's why there's a vertical line here in the middle,
这就是为什么这里会有一条竖线
which is meant to convey the concept of one in binary.
它表示了二进制中的“一”
But, of course, hydrogen is merely one of many
当然，氢元素大概只是
possible interpretations of this diagram.
这张图的一种解释方式
The aliens could just as easily think it's some sort of language,
外星人可能认为它只是某种语言
technology, star system, or literally anything else.
技术，星系，或者其他什么东西
To help them narrow down the list, the plaque includes three outlined silhouettes
为了帮它们缩小范围
These illustrations were drawn to scale,
这些插图按比例绘制
so the aliens can use the spacecraft's diameter
所以外星人可以使用飞船的直径
as a basis for deriving the height of the two figures in the foreground.
作为推算前景中的两人身高的基础
In human terms, that would make the man approximately 182 centimeters
在人类的视角看，男人身高大概会是 182 厘米
and the woman about 169.
女人身高大概 169 厘米
The woman's height has been further emphasized
位于右边缘的两条界标
by two demarcation marks along the right edge here.
再度强调了女人的身高
Between them is a sequence of four lines representing the number eight in binary.
界标之间有四条线，代表着二进制中的数字八
The purpose of this number is to communicate to the aliens
这个数字用来告诉外星人
that the woman is eight times as tall as the wavelength of the hydrogen line.
那个女人的身高是氢线波长的八倍
In human terms, that's about 169,
用人类的表示，这大概是 169 厘米
just like the woman's height relative to the probe's diameter.
就跟使用探测器的直径算得的女人身高差不多
In other words, the interpretation of this as a schematic of hydrogen
换句话说，将这里看作是氢的示意图
and the interpretation of this as an outline of the spacecraft
然后将这里看作是一个飞船的轮廓
are mutually corroborative.
是具有相互佐证作用的
They provide the aliens with a means of deriving the height of this figure
他们基于两种不同的测量方式
on the basis of two distinct measurements,
为外星人提供了确定人物高度的方法
which should help them narrow down the list of possible interpretations.
这应该有助于外星人缩小解释的范围
At least, that was the idea.
至少，这就是这些想法的目的所在
But when you actually measure the height of the couple
但当你真正相对于这个探测器
relative to this sketch of the probe,
来测量这对男女的高度
you quickly realize they're about 10 centimeters too tall.
你会很快意识到他们多出了10厘米
While I have no way of confirming this, I suspect the source of this discrepancy
虽然我无法证实此事，但我怀疑这种差异
is that the reflector dish on Pioneer 10 is not a perfect circle.
是由先驱者十号的反射盘不是一个完美的圆形导致的
It's slightly wider in this dimension than in this one,
这个轴的长度比另一个轴的要略长
known as a major and minor axis.
它们分别是主轴和次轴
If we assume that this outline of the probe
如果假设这个探测器的轮廓
is oriented with the minor axis along the vertical,
以次轴作为竖直方向对齐
the relative height of the couple is indeed what you'd expect.
他们的相对身高应该就是正常的
But if that is what the Sagans and Drake intended,
但如果萨根和德雷克真的是这样做的
only two of the three antenna struts should be visible here in the front.
前面应该只能看见三条中的两条天线支撑杆
The fact that all three have been drawn on the plaque,
而镀金铝板上面把三条支撑杆都画了出来
implies the probe is oriented with the major axis along the vertical,
这意味着探测器以主轴作为垂直方向对齐
thereby increasing the couples' height by roughly 10 centimeters.
从而使男女的身高都增加了约十厘米
Nevertheless, it's hardly surprising for an oversight like this to go unnoticed
尽管如此，这种疏忽也无可厚非
given they only had three weeks to assemble everything,
他们毕竟只有三个星期来完成所有事情
and Sagan acknowledged they could have done a better job
并且萨根也承认如果没有那么赶时间
had they not been so pressed for time.
他们可以做得更好
Moving on to the left side of the plaque,
来看镀金铝板的左侧
we find a starburst pattern of 15 straight lines emanating from a central point.
我们会发现一个星形爆炸图，十五条直线从一个中心点发散出来
This is a galactic map of pulsars
这是一个脉冲星的星系图
that's meant to help the aliens pinpoint the Solar System.
它帮助外星人定位到太阳系
Pulsars are rapidly rotating neutron stars that can easily be spotted
脉冲星是快速旋转的中子星
They're often described as cosmic clocks or
他们经常被描述为宇宙的时钟
lighthouses because they're not only extremely bright
或者灯塔，因为它们不仅非常明亮
but pulsate at very consistent rates.
而且以非常统一的速率跳动
This red line shooting off to the right
这条射向右侧的红线
represents the distance between the Sun and the center of the galaxy,
代表着太阳与银河系中心的距离
while the green lines represent the relative distance
而绿线代表
between the Sun and 14 pulsars.
太阳和十四颗脉冲星的相对距离
To make it easier to identify the pulsars,
为了更容易认出这些脉冲星
each line is accompanied by the star's rotation period expressed in binary,
每条线都伴随着以二进制表示的自转周期
marked here in blue.
在这里标为蓝色
Take this one, for instance.
以这个为例
This star is known as the Vela Pulsar, and it's about 1 000 lightyears from Earth.
这个星被称为船帆座脉冲星，距离地球约 1000 光年
Its rotation period has been expressed in waveperiods of the hydrogen line
它的自转周期用氢线的频率来表示
and reads 126 726 823 when translated from binary to decimal.
将二进制转换为十进制得到一亿两千六百七十二万六千八百二十三
What that means is that it takes the Vela Pulsar
这意味着船帆座脉冲星
almost 127 million times longer to complete one rotation
完成一次自转需要大概 1.27 亿倍的
than the waveperiod of a hydrogen atom undergoing hyperfine transition.
氢原子超精细跃迁的时间
In human terms, that's about 89 million nanoseconds or
用人话说，就是八千九百万纳秒
eleven rotations every second, which is about this fast.
或者 11 转每秒，大概是这么快
By scouring the galaxy for pulsars
通过在星系中寻找
that match the information embedded within this map,
与这个星图中的信息相匹配的脉冲星
the aliens could theoretically triangulate the Solar System.
外星人理论上可以三角测量太阳系
In fact, the chart not only discloses our location in space but also in time.
事实上，这张图不仅披露了我们的空间位置，也披露我们的时间位置
As Sagan put it...
正如萨根说的...
[Carl Sagan] Where we are, when we are, and who we are.
“我们存在于何处，我们存在于何时，以及我们是谁”
This goes back to the cosmic clock analogy
这回到了宇宙时钟的那个类比
because pulsars gradually wind down at highly predictable rates.
脉冲星的速度以一种可预测的速率逐渐减慢
So even though the Vela Pulsar will have a much slower rate of spin
即使在我们假想的外星人发现船帆座脉冲星时
by the time it's observed by our hypothetical aliens,
它的转速减慢了
they could simply wind back the clock until its rotation period
它们也可以直接反拨这个时钟，直到其旋转周期
matched the one etched into the plaque.
与镀金铝板上的相匹配
Repeating that process for at least some of the other pulsars
对其他的脉冲星重复相同的流程
would enable them to figure out not just from where,
就可以让他们不仅推断出先驱者是从哪来的
but also when Pioneer 10 was launched.
也能推断出其的发射时间
At least, that was the idea.
至少，这就是当时的想法所在
But when the plaque was created,
但在制造这块镀金铝板的时候
the existence of pulsars had only been known for about four years.
人类了解脉冲星也不过四年
Astronomers have since learned a lot more about them,
天文学家后来有了更多的了解
and they're not nearly as rare, stable, and long-lived as once believed.
脉冲星不再是之前认为的那样稀有、稳定且长久存在
They can only be observed from very specific vantage points, and
它们只能从一个非常特殊且恰好的角度才能观察到
unpredictable speedups, slowdowns, and glitches
并且还有一些无法预测的加减速和抖动
challenge the cosmic clock analogy.
这让宇宙时钟的比喻变得不再牢靠
Sagan and Drake were aware of at least
萨根和德雷克至少意识到了一部分问题
some of these issues, but there was only so much they could've foreseen
但受制于当时有限的信息
with the limited data available at the time.
他们也只能预见一小部分
In fact, there was such great uncertainty
事实上，由于这里的某些脉冲星的距离
regarding the distance of some of the featured pulsars
存在相当大的不确定性
that they added these breaks in the lines,
他们在连线上添加了这些间断
indicating they're based on rough estimates rather than exact figures.
表示这里的数字是粗略的估计而非精确的数值
Finally, on the bottom of the plaque,
最后，在镀金铝板的底部
we find a plain schematic of the Solar System.
我们可以看到太阳系的朴素图示
These binary numbers represent the orbital distance of each planet
这些二进制数字代表每个行星的轨道半径
expressed as multiples of one tenth of the mean distance between the Sun and Mercury.
以太阳和水星之间的平均距离的十分之一为单位表示
For instance, the number above Earth reads 26 in decimal,
例如，在地球上方这个数字的十进制是 26
which means it is 26 times further away
这意味着地球与太阳的距离是二十六倍远的
than 10% of the distance between the Sun and Mercury.
十分之一太阳与水星距离
The obvious problem with this approach
这种方法存在一个明显的问题
is that it requires the recipients to already be familiar with the Solar System.
它需要接收者比较熟悉太阳系
Otherwise, one tenth of the distance between the Sun and Mercury
否则，太阳和水星之间的距离的十分之一
is completely meaningless.
完全没有意义
We might as well have expected them to be familiar with kilometers or miles.
我们或许还假设了他们熟悉公里或英里
To quote the creators of the plaque...
引用镀金铝板创造者的话…
It's unclear why the Sagans and Drake
我们并不清楚为什么萨根和德雷克
knowingly used an indecipherable unit of length
故意使用了一个无法解码的长度单位
when they had already gone through the trouble of creating a universal yardstick
即使他们已经经受了用氢的示意图
with this schematic of hydrogen.
来制造一个通用度量的重重困难
My best guess is that the wavelength of a state-shifting hydrogen atom
我最好的猜测是，用一个小小的氢原子激发出的波长
was simply too small a unit to represent interplanetary distances,
来表示行星之间的距离实在太小
and the resulting binary strings became too long to neatly fit on the plaque.
由此产生的二进制会很长，在铝板上会排不下
Again, they only had three weeks to do all of this.
并且他们只有三个星期来完成这一切
Last but not least, the trajectory of the spacecraft has been traced with an arrow,
最后同样值得注意的是，这飞船的轨迹用一条箭头标了出来
and the probe's main antenna is pointing at home.
探测器的主天线正对着家园
Over half a century later,
五十多年后
Pioneer 10 is now more than 20 billion kilometers from the Sun.
先驱者十号探测器与太阳的距离已超过 200 亿公里
That might sound like a lot, especially given how I just emphasized that number,
这或许听上去很多，并且刚刚我也着重强调了这个数字
but it's only about three times further away than Pluto,
但这也只是冥王星与太阳距离的三倍
and it takes less than a day for a light beam to cover the same distance.
光用不到一天的时间就能走过
Even though it's darting through space at several kilometers per second,
尽管探测器以每秒数千米的速度穿梭于空间之间
the probe won't surpass even the nearest star to the Sun
但它就算走过数万年
for many tens of thousands of years.
也不会到达距离太阳最近的那颗恒星
But it gets worse because Pioneer 10 is not headed for any particular star.
更严重的是，先驱者十号并没有朝着具体哪颗恒星进发
It's expected to pass within a few trillion kilometers of a relatively nearby system
大概在九万年后，它将走过几万亿公里
in about 90 000 years or so when this star, all the way out here,
掠过一个相对邻近的恒星系统
will come closer to the Sun than Proxima Centauri is today.
也将比如今的比邻星更接近太阳
While an exoplanet has yet to be detected around this star,
虽然还没有探测到在这个恒星周围的行星
if one does exist, and that planet just so happens to be inhabited
但如果恰好存在一个行星
by intelligent beings in possession of technology that allows them to detect a
其上居住着智慧生命，且它们具有一定科技
perfectly silent and practically invisible speck gently gliding by their system
能探测到一个静悄悄、几乎隐形的小颗粒
at a distance greater than a thousand times the orbit of Pluto,
在比冥王星轨道长几千倍的距离划过它们的系统
then, yeah...
那么，嗯...
...maybe they'll see it.
...或许它们就能发现这个探测器了
A nearly identical probe was launched in 1973 known as Pioneer 11,
与十号几乎一模一样的先驱者十一号在 1973 年发射升空
and it was outfitted with the exact same plaque as Pioneer 10.
其上配有与十号一样的镀金铝板
Much like its predecessor, Pioneer 11 was just kind of hurtled into deep space
就像它的前代一样，先驱者十一号也只是一股脑冲向深空
with no particular target in mind.
并没有什么特定的目标
While a chance encounter with another planetary system is not impossible,
尽管在数十亿年的时间尺度上
even across timescales of many billions of years,
与另一个星系的偶遇并非不可能
Sagan and Drake believed it was more likely
但萨根和德雷克认为更有可能的情况是
for the probes to be scooped up by an alien spaceship
这些探测器会被在群星之间航行的
traveling between the stars.
外星飞船捡到
Some studies have shown that space is, in fact,
一些研究表明，宇宙其实
a tiny bit big.
有那么点...大
It's very easy to criticize the Pioneer Plaques.
先驱者镀金铝板确实并非完美
Any message designed to be understood by beings of which we know nothing about will
任何旨在被我们一无所知的生物理解的信息
unavoidably rely upon assumptions that could easily be false.
不可避免地依赖于一些很可能错误的假设
Will the aliens understand the meaning of an arrow?
外星人会知道箭头是什么意思吗？
Will they comprehend binary notation?
它们会理解二进制的记号吗？
Will they even grasp the concept of conveying information
再退一步说，它们能理解“使用二维图示来传递信息”
using two-dimensional pictograms?
是一种什么概念吗？
While questions like these are perfectly valid,
这些问题都是合理的
they're ultimately quite pointless because the answer is always the same.
但因为答案总是一样而变得没有意义——
We don't know.
我们一无所知
We don't know what the aliens look like, how they think, or even if they exist.
我们不知道外星人长什么样，他们是怎么想的，甚至不知道他们是否存在
The plaque could be so at odds with how they perceive and navigate the universe
这块铝板可能与他们感知和探索宇宙的方式相悖
they fail to even recognize it as a message
他们甚至可能不认为这是一种信息
or we might be foolish for thinking a civilization so technologically advanced
或者我们也可能愚蠢地认为一个技术如此发达的文明
they're able to locate and retrieve a derelict spacecraft from the dead of space
他们都能够从太空的死寂中定位并回收废弃的飞船
will be stumped by an interstellar cave painting.
还会困于一个星际壁画
While many believe the recipients will be nothing like us,
许多人认为接收者与我们天差地别
we could just as easily have a lot in common.
但我们同样也可能有很多相同点
After all, we share the same universe
毕竟，我们都在同一个宇宙里
and are therefore shaped and bound by the same physical laws of nature.
因而天然被相同物理定律塑造和约束
In fact, that's what some people fear the most.
其实这就是一部分人最害怕的一件事
That the aliens could be just like us.
即外星人可能和我们差不多
That they could inflict upon us what we inflict upon members of our own species.
这样他们就有可能用我们对待自己同类的方式对待我们
The Sagans and Drake tried to get ahead of these concerns
萨根夫妇和德雷克回应过这些担忧
by emphasizing the improbability of interception.
他们强调探测器被截获的可能性极低
They stressed that, even if the probes were to fall into the tentacles
他们指出，即使探测器在遥远的未来
of a hostile intelligence in some distant future,
被一种敌对的生物所截获
they'd be too far away to pose a threat.
他们也会因为与我们相距太远而造不成什么威胁
But statistics and probability only get you so far
但统计学和概率论的说服力毕竟有限
because fear is a powerful emotion.
因为恐惧是一种很强烈的情绪
[George Wald] And may I say so that we can have a
我斗胆说几点
somewhat warmer and livelier conversation as this meeting goes on.
来让这次会议更加热烈生动
I can conceive of no nightmare as terrifying as establishing such communication
我无法想象有比这更可怕的噩梦——
with a so-called superior or, if you wish, advanced technology in outer space.
与某种所谓的更高等，或者你愿意的话，更“先进”的外太空文明建立起那样的联系
A year after the launch of Pioneer 11, the Arecibo Radio Observatory,
先驱者十一号发射的一年后，位于波多黎各丛林深处的
located deep within the jungles of Puerto Rico, received a major facelift.
阿雷西博射电天文台获得重大翻新
The telescope was not only resurfaced to greatly increase its sensitivity,
射电望远镜的表面不仅被重铺来大幅提高敏感度
but also outfitted with a powerful transmitter.
其还配备了一个强力的发射台
As it happens, the man in charge of the research center overseeing the facility
很巧的是，当时负责监管这个设施中心的人
was none other than Frank Drake.
恰好是弗兰克·德雷克
To celebrate the telescope's upgraded capabilities,
为了庆祝望远镜的升级
Drake's assistant, Jane Allen,
德雷克的助手，简·艾伦
suggested they transmit an interstellar message
建议他们在即将到来的落成典礼上
during the upcoming rededication ceremony.
发射一条星际信息
Unlike the tangible Pioneer Plaques,
与实体形式的先驱者镀金铝板不同
the Arecibo Message had to be communicated using invisible radio waves.
阿雷西博信息以不可见的无线电波传达
Drake had previously experimented with the idea
德雷克之前试验过这一想法
of transmitting an image coded in binary,
传输了一张二进制编码的图片
and with the help of some colleagues and graduate students, he came up with this.
在同事和研究生们的帮助下，他想出了这个东西
Now, this may not look like much,
此刻，我们可能看不出什么
but if we fill in all the zeros with black squares
但如果我们将所有 0 处填为黑色
and all the ones with white squares,
1 处填为白色
a highly pixelated image will emerge.
就会显现出一张高度像素化的图像
I'll explain the different parts in just a moment,
我稍后会解释其中的不同部分
but first, it's important to understand how an image like this
但首先，我们得知道像这样的一张图片
is converted into radio waves.
是如何被转换为无线电波的
It starts with a grid that, in this case, is 23 columns wide and 73 rows tall
这始于一个网格，在这种情况下，具有 23 列宽、73 行高
for a total of 1 679 cells.
总共有一千六百七十九个格子
We then fill in the cells needed to create the image.
我们填充其中的一些格子来画出这张图片
Because the image is composed of only two shades, black and white,
由于该图像只有黑白两种颜色
that means it's binary,
意味着它具有二进制特征
and each cell can also be described as a binary digit, or bit for short.
每一格就可以用一个二进制位，或简称“位”，来表示
By convention, binary code is expressed using zeros and ones,
习惯上，二进制代码用零和一来表示
but it works just as well with two different shapes, two different colors,
但也可以用两种不同的形状、两种不同的颜色
two different rocks, or literally any combination of two contrasting values.
两种不同的石头，甚至任何两种不同值的组合来表示
In fact, that's why binary code is so frequently used
其实这就是为什么二进制代码如此广泛用于
to write interstellar messages.
编写星际信息
It's not because aliens are guaranteed to understand it.
这并不是因为外星人一定能理解它
No, it's simply one of the least complicated methods
不是的，只是因为这是一种不那么复杂的
of conveying information that we can imagine.
用来传递我们能想象的信息的方法
Chinese is composed of thousands of characters,
中文由数千个字符组成
English has 26 letters,
英文有二十六个字母
while decimal demands 10 unique numerals.
十进制基于十个不同的数字
Binary only requires two.
而二进制，只要两个
Not two letters, not two symbols, literally just two of something, which we call bits.
不一定是两个字母、两个符号，仅仅是两个“东西”，我们称之为位
For instance, instead of black and white squares,
例如，如果不用黑白块来表示
we could just as easily express this bitmap using two different frequencies.
我们也可以用两种不同的频率来表达这个位图
If a cell is black, that's one frequency.
某个格子是黑的，那就分配一个频率
If it's white, that's another.
是白的，就用另一个频率
There you go. That's all there's to it.
就这样，没别的
This long sequence of two flip-flopping frequencies
这一长串不断交替的频率
can now be transmitted using a radio telescope.
就可以用射电望远镜来传输
When that signal is picked up by an alien astronomer,
当这一信号被一个外星天文学家接收到时
they may find it difficult to ascribe such an unnatural pattern to a natural source.
他们就不太能认为这么不自然的音形来自于自然
This will hopefully draw attention to the number of frequency fluctuations because
这大概率会引起他们对频率波动的关注
1 679 is what's known as a semiprime.
因为 1679 是一个半质数
It's disappointingly not the half-brother of Optimus Prime,
所谓半质数，很遗憾并不是擎天柱同父异母的兄弟
but rather the product of precisely two prime numbers.
而是两个质数的乘积
In this case, those prime numbers are 23 and 73,
在这里，这两个质数是 23 和 73
which happens to be the dimensions of the original grid.
恰好就是之前网格的尺寸
If the aliens were to plot the frequencies onto a grid of that size
如果外星人将频率画在这样的网格上
and fill in all the cells occupied by one of the values,
然后填写其中一种频率对应的所有格子
they would uncover the image.
就能看到这幅图像了
As for the contents of the message,
至于这则消息的内容
it starts off easy enough with the numbers 1 through 10 expressed in binary
开始的地方很简单，是二进制的一到十
and written from right-to-left.
将它们从右往左写
So 0-0-1, 0-1-0, 0-1-1, and so on.
也就是 0-0-1，0-1-0，0-1-1，等
Moving on to this large cluster of pixels,
现在来看这一大簇的像素
we find a bunch of binary formulations for the building blocks of life as we know it.
我们会发现一堆我们熟知的生命基本构成单位的二进制表示
It starts with the atomic numbers of five basic elements:
它从五个基本元素的原子序数开始：
hydrogen, carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, and phosphorus.
氢, 碳, 氮, 氧, 磷
These numbers are then used to describe essential components of DNA.
后面用这些数字来表示 DNA 的基本组成部分
For instance, a carbon atom has six protons,
例如，一个碳原子有六个质子
which means it has an atomic number of six.
也就是它的原子序数为六
0-1-1-0 is binary for decimal 6.
0-1-1-0 是十进制六的二进制表示
Because carbon is in the second column from the right,
碳位于从右数第二列
it means the second column of these molecules underneath
这表示下面这些分子的第二列
indicates how many carbon atoms they contain.
表示他们有多少个碳原子
So these four represent an organic compound known as deoxyribose,
这里的四个表示一种叫作脱氧核糖的有机化合物
which has five carbon atoms, and 1-0-1 is binary for decimal 5.
它有五个碳原子，1-0-1 是十进制的 5
In the center of the image, we find a crude rendition of the DNA double helix
在图像的中心，我们可以看到 DNA 双螺旋结构的一个粗糙表示
enclosing a large binary value
其中包含了一个大的二进制值
denoting the number of nucleotide base pairs in the human genome.
这表示人类基因组中的碱基个数
In simpler terms, it's a way of expressing the complexity or
简单来说，这是一种用来表示
size of our genetic makeup.
我们基因组成的复杂性和庞大性的方式
However, more recent measurements have since reduced that number by over a billion,
然而，更近的测量结果将碱基个数减掉了十亿多
so this figure is no longer accurate.
所以这个数字不再准确了
A bit further down, we find a simple sketch of a human,
稍微往下一点，我们可以看到简笔画的人
alongside an expression of their height on the right
他的右边是他的身高
and the estimated global population in 1974 on the left.
左边是 1974 年全球人口数量的估计值
Directly underneath the human is a schematic of the Solar System,
这个人的这个下方是一张太阳系的示意图
followed by an illustration of the Arecibo Telescope.
以及阿雷西博望远镜的示意图
Now, you might be wondering,
现在，你可能会想
"How the hell were the aliens supposed to understand any of that?"
“外星人怎么能理解这上面哪怕任何一个部分呢？”
The simple answer is, they weren't really.
简单来说，这并不是要让外星人理解的东西
Unlike the Pioneer Plaques' commendable attempt
与先驱者镀金铝板值得称颂的尝试——
to establish some sort of common ground using shared units of measurement
用相同的测量单位来建立某种基础共识
and a galactic map of pulsars,
提供一个脉冲星的星图等不同的是
the Arecibo Message was much more of a publicity stunt.
阿雷西博信息更多是一种对外的展示
For instance, the length of the message
比如这条信息的长度
was largely determined by the presumed attention span
大幅度取决于那些被邀请参加落成典礼的人
of those invited to the rededication ceremony.
能给予注意力的时长
The concern was that, if the message was too long,
如果当时发的消息太长
attendees might be annoyed by the sound of the transmission,
参会者可能会被发射的声音吵到
which was planned to be broadcast over loudspeakers at the event.
这发射的声音在典礼期间是用音响广播播放的
In the end, the message was constrained to about three minutes
最后，这条消息被定在大概三分钟左右
to mitigate the risk of a dull afternoon.
从而避免让一这下午都变得无趣
Likewise, the selection of a target for the transmission was entirely dictated
同样，发射目标的选择
by what happened to be visible in the sky during the ceremony.
也完全由活动当时能在天上看到什么来决定
Drake ultimately selected a bright cluster of stars known as Messier 13,
德雷克最终选了当时比较亮的一个星团，M13 球状星团
which is about 24 000 lightyears from Earth.
大概离地球两万四千光年
While this meant the message would take 24 000 years to reach its destination,
这距离表示信息需要花费两万四千年才能抵达
the density of M13 also meant the signal could sweep over many
M13 的密度还意味着这一信号会在到达之时
thousands of stars upon arrival.
掠过成千上万的星星
At the time, this was thought to maximize the odds of the transmission being received,
当时认为这会大大提高信息被接收到的概率
and Carl Sagan even told a reporter
卡尔·萨根甚至告诉记者
that he believed there was a 50% chance that M13 was home to an alien civilization.
他认为 M13 有一半的概率是外星文明的家园
But as it turns out, more stars
但事实上，更多的星星
does not necessarily mean more opportunities for life.
并不代表着更大的生命存在概率
Not only are globular clusters like M13 typically starved of heavier elements
像 M13 这样的球状星团
essential for planetary formation,
不仅极度缺少对行星形成至关重要的重元素
but the proximity of the stars makes it challenging for any planets that do form
而且因为恒星挨得太近，即使真的形成行星
to maintain stable orbits.
它们也很难维持稳定的轨道
Considering it took billions of years before humans evolved on Earth,
地球经历几十亿年才有了人类
a region as densely packed and chaotic as M13
一个像 M13 这样紧密、混乱的区域
is probably not the most conducive environment for life as we know it.
大概率不是我们所认为的宜居环境
While there is some optimism that small planets like Earth
我们仍可以乐观地认为，小如地球这样的行星
could survive in very tight orbits,
也能在很狭窄的轨道上面持续存在
out of six thousand exoplanets discovered to date,
但截至目前已经发现的六千个系外行星中
only two are located within a globuluster.
只有两个是存在于球状星团中的
Nevertheless, on November 16, 1974,
无论如何，在 1974 年 11 月 16 日
a small crowd of astronomers, dignitaries, and others
一小群天文学家、达官贵人等
bopped along to a three-minute concert of two warbling tones
在一场三分钟音乐会中，伴着两段婉转的旋律翩翩起舞
as humanity's first interstellar radiotelegram was beamed into space.
人类的第一颗星际电报被发射到太空中
A common misconception about the Arecibo Message
一个关于阿雷西博信息的常见误解是
is that it will miss its target because the telescope was aimed at the position of M13
它没有特定的目标，因为发射时望远镜对向的是 M13 的位置
at the time of transmission, rather than where it will be in 24 000 years.
而不是在两万四千年之后会到达的一个特定目的地
In reality, when Drake crunched the numbers back in 1974,
1974 年，德雷克实际计算数字的时候
he realized that the cluster was so enormous and slow-moving
他发现这个星团非常巨大且移动缓慢
that even if they aimed the telescope at its location at the time,
即使当时用望远镜瞄准了一个位置
the message would simply strike slightly off-center rather than a bullseye.
消息也会偏离目标一点点，而不是正中靶心
Presuming against all odds that M13 is home to an alien civilization
抛开所有可能的问题，假设 M13 确实存在一个外星文明
in possession of an extremely sensitive instrument that's not only designed
并且他们有灵敏度极高的仪器
to pick up radio waves at the exact same frequency and bandwidth
不仅能在与阿雷西博信号完全相同的频率和带宽上
at which the Arecibo Message was transmitted,
接收无线电波
but also pointed squarely at the Solar System at just the right time,
而且还在恰好的时间正对着太阳系
Messierian astronomers will have a non-zero chance
那么 M13 的天文学家才会有不为零的概率
to detect a non-repeating burst of energy lasting for less than three minutes
在距今两万四千年以后探测到一阵
some 24 000 years from now.
只有一次的、持续少于三分钟的能量的迸发
Even though they're unlikely to decode the message,
他们尽管不太可能将这段信息解码出来
they might still suspect it's an attempt at communication.
但也可能怀疑这是一种建立沟通的尝试
It's a bit like, even if you don't speak Swedish...
这有点像，即使你听不懂瑞典语...
*SWEDISH NOISES*
*瑞典噪音*
If they suspect it's a transmission from another civilization,
如果他们怀疑这是一种来自其他文明的信号
the aliens may choose to respond.
外星人可能会决定回应的
Presuming there's no way to overcome the speed of light,
如果没有超越光速的方法
such a response would obviously take just as long to reach us
这样的回应无疑会花费与阿雷西博信息抵达那里
as it took the Arecibo Message to reach them.
一样长的时间才能到达我们这里
Based on the most recent measurements of the distance between the Solar System and M13,
根据最近一次对太阳系与 M13 之间距离的测量
the earliest possible date we can expect a reply
我们最早收到回复的时间
is the year 50370.
是公元 50370 年
Don't forget to mark your calendars.
别忘了在你的日历上标出来
There are even more hopelessly optimistic scenarios,
其实还有更多不太可能的乐观场景
like a star or spaceship crossing paths with the signal somewhere along the way.
比如某颗星星或者飞船与信号在路上相遇了
But the odds of that happening are so vanishingly small
但这发生的几率非常微小
it might as well be impossible.
就跟不可能差不多
Not least of all because, as you can see,
尤其值得注意的是，如你所见
M13 is actually floating far above the galactic disc,
M13 实际上漂浮在银河系盘面的上方很远的地方
and there's a whole lot of nothing in between.
这之间空无一物
But, once again, these astronomical improbabilities
但，还是一样，这种天文上的不太可能
were not enough to allay concerns of an alien invasion.
并不足以消除对外星入侵的担忧
A prominent radio astronomer in Britain at the time, Sir Martin Ryle,
当时英国的著名射电天文学家，马丁·赖尔爵士
feared the Arecibo Message might attract a more advanced civilization
担心阿雷西博消息可能吸引一种更高等的文明
seeking to colonize the Earth and mine its resources.
来殖民地球然后开采资源
He took issue with the fact that a small group of people had transmitted a message
他对这一小群人发出了一条
that could endanger all of humanity,
可能会危及全人类的信息感到不满
and called for an international discussion in advance of any future transmissions.
并呼吁在未来的一切发送之前都要进行国际讨论
While these concerns largely fell on deaf ears at the time,
虽然这种担忧大部分都被充耳不闻
Ryle was far from the only one urging caution.
赖尔远非唯一一个呼吁谨慎行事的人
By the mid-1970s, NASA was gearing up to launch two spacecraft
二十世纪七十年代中期，NASA 正筹备发射两艘航天器
known as Voyager 1 and 2.
即旅行者 1 号和 2 号
Much like the Pioneer probes before them,
像之前的先驱者探测器一样
the Voyager twins would be slingshot into deep space by granddaddy Jupiter
这一对旅行者双胞胎也会被木星爷爷抛入深空
on their way to explore the outer Solar System.
从而踏上探索太阳系外的旅程
Due to the similarity between the two programs
由于两项计划十分相似
and the public interest generated by the Pioneer Plaques,
并且先驱者镀金铝板引起了公众兴趣
NASA engineer John Casani thought a similar message
NASA 工程师约翰·卡萨尼认为
ought to be carried by the Voyagers.
应该让旅行者也携带一条类似的信息
When Casani reached out to Carl Sagan in late 1976,
卡萨尼在一九七六年年末给卡尔·萨根写信后
he jumped at the chance to scribe another cosmic postcard.
他欣然接收了编绘又一张宇宙明星片的机会
But this time, he wanted to impress upon the recipients not just how we think,
这一次，他想要让接收者不仅能感受到我们怎么想
but also how we feel.
还要能感受到我们有什么感受
After consulting numerous people on how to proceed,
在咨询了多方关于如何开展的意见后
two propositions stood above the rest: music and pictures.
这两个提议格外亮眼：音乐和图片
Sagan was partial to music while fellow astronomer Frank Drake
萨根对音乐的想法情有独钟，而弗兰克·德雷克
thought nothing could capture the human condition like a series of photographs.
认为没有什么能比照片更好地体现人类现状
After some additional brainstorming, it was Drake who finally realized
经过又一些头脑风暴，德雷克终于意识到
they could accommodate both ideas using a phonograph record.
他们可以用唱片来同时实现两种想法
A phonograph record is an analog storage medium,
唱片是一种模拟存储介质
primarily used to record and replay sound.
主要用于录制和回放声音
To record, you simply press a needle against the surface of a slow-spinning disc.
录制的时候，只需将针抵住缓慢旋转的盘面
By generating a sound, like strumming a guitar...
然后发出声音，比如拨动一把吉他...
...the needle will start to vibrate as it carves a thin
...针会开始振动，
undulating groove into the disc.
然后在盘面上雕刻出细细的深浅不一的凹槽
To replay the sound, you simply create a copy of the disc
要将声音回放出来，你只需用一种不太容易变形的材料
using a less malleable material,
造出唱片的一张拷贝
place the needle back at the beginning of the groove,
然后将针头放回凹槽的起始位置
and spin the disc back up again.
再次旋转唱片
As the needle collides with the
当针与凹槽中
hundreds of microscopic indentations in the groove,
数百微小的凹痕碰撞
it generates the same vibrations used to create it.
它会产生与这些凹痕产生时相同的震动
When those vibrations reach your ears, you'll hear a guitar being strummed.
这些振动传到你的耳朵，你就会听到一把吉他被拨动的声音
The process is a bit more complicated in practice, of course,
现实中，这个过程显然会更复杂
but honestly, not by much.
但说实话，也并没有复杂多少
Whether it's a single vibrating guitar string
无论是一根吉他弦线的振动
or the deafening crescendo of an entire orchestra,
还是整个管弦乐队震耳欲聋的渐强
all of it can be recorded and replayed by tiny bumps in a grove.
所有的一切都可以被凹槽中微小的凸起中记录并播放
Yes, magic is real, and this is it.
没错，魔法其实真的存在，这就是魔法
But what about the photographs?
那么照片该怎么办呢？
How do you get visual information onto a storage medium made for sound?
如何将视觉信息存储在一种为声音而设计的介质上呢？
It's surprisingly simple, actually.
其实这意外地简单
Remember how the Arecibo Message painted a picture
还记得阿雷西博信息通过将黑白方块
by treating black and white squares as two different frequencies?
视为两种不同的频率来记录一张图片吗？
I mean, it would be a bit concerning if you don't.
如果你已经忘了的话就有点令人担忧了
That was just 12 minutes ago. You better get that checked out.
这才过了十二分钟。你最好再去看看
Anyway, they basically did that, but instead of just two frequencies,
按你胃，他们基本上就是这么做的，只不过不是用的两个频率
they used a whole range of them.
而是范围内的所有的频率
Take a gradient like this, for instance.
比如像这样的一个渐变
If we assign a low frequency to black...
如果将低频率分配给黑色...
...and a high frequency to white...
...以及把高频率分配给白色...
...then every shade of gray in between
...然后中间不同深度的灰色
will be mapped to a corresponding frequency of sound.
就会被映射到声音相应的频率上
With that translation scheme in mind,
有了这种转译的思想
converting an entire photograph becomes trivial.
将整张图片转换成声音就易如反掌了
For instance, this is a black-and-white image of Mercury that's actually on the record.
例如，这是一张水星的黑白图片，也是真正存在于那张唱片的图片
All we have to do is scan every pixel in this image,
我们所要做的就是将图片上的每一个像素扫描一遍
one by one, column by column,
一个一个，一列一列
and translate every shade of gray into its audible equivalent.
然后将每一个灰阶转换为它的声学等价
Once we've translated every frequency of light into a frequency of sound,
只要我们将每个光的频率转换为音的频率
we end up with a brief sample of incoherent noise
我们就会得到一个无意义噪声的简单样本
that acts like an acoustic fingerprint of the image.
它就像图像的声学指纹
Again, I'm simplifying a lot here, and the actual process used analog signals
依旧，我在这里简化了很多，实际过程中用的是模拟信号
rather than quantized pixel values, but it gives you a rough idea of how it was done.
而不是量化的像素值，但在这里它可以帮你了解大概的原理
Some photographs were actually recorded three times in a row
一部分图片实际上被同时录了三次
using filters for red, green, and blue.
分别用到了红色、绿色和蓝色滤镜
When recombined in just the right way,
当他们被以合适的方式重新组合起来时
they produce an image full of vibrant colors,
就会产生一张具有鲜艳色彩的图像
even though, individually, they're all black and white.
尽管单独来看，它们都是黑白的
Again, magic is real.
再说一遍，魔法是真实存在的
In an effort to save space, they also recorded
为了节省空间，他们还在同一个凹槽中
two simultaneous streams of images into the same groove.
录制了两个并行的图像音频
This was accomplished by using the side-to-side motion of the needle
这是通过让针左右移动
to record one stream,
来录制其中一个音频
and the up-and-down motion to record another.
上下运动来记录另一个音频而实现的
The end result was this echoey stereo sound of two image streams playing at once.
最终结果是两个图像的这种带有回响的立体声音同时播放
To provide the aliens with the best possible chance
为了让外星人以最大概率
of decoding this cryptic disc of gold-plated copper,
解码这个神秘的镀金铜板
the record's aluminum cover was engraved with some basic instructions.
这张唱片的铝盖上蚀刻了一些基本步骤
First of all, the pulsar map makes a return,
脉冲星图首先回归了
and so, too, does the diagram showing the hyperfine transition of neutral hydrogen.
然后同样的，中性氢原子的超精细跃迁图也还在
The latter of which is, once again, used to establish
后者依然是为了
a shared unit of both time and length.
建立起时间和长度的共同单位
Near the top left, we find an overhead view of the record
在左上角，我们可以看见唱片的俯视图
circumscribed by a binary number.
外部标着一个二进制数字
It's telling the aliens to spin the record about five billion times faster
这告诉外星人要将唱片以五十亿倍于
than the hyperfine transition period.
超精细跃迁周期的速度进行旋转
In human terms, that's equivalent to roughly one rotation every 3.6 seconds.
用人话说，大约相当于每 3.6 秒一圈
To ensure the aliens have something with which to play the record,
为了确保外星人有播放唱片的工具
a ceramic cartridge holding a diamond-tipped needle
一个具有金刚石尖端的陶瓷卡针
was attached to the mounting bracket.
放在了支架上
An outline of this cartridge has also been drawn along the right edge here
卡针的轮廓画在了右边缘这里
to indicate the playback starting position.
表示这里是播放的起始位置
Underneath the overhead view, there's also a side view,
在俯视图下面，还有一个侧视图
accompanied by another binary number.
旁边是另一个二进制数字
This time, it's telling the aliens how long it takes to play
这个数字是告诉外星人
one full side of the record, which is about 54 minutes.
完整播放唱片的一面需要多久，大约 54 分钟
Moving on to the top right, we find a step-by-step guide
在右上角，我们可以看到
for decoding the images.
解码图像的分步指引
The waveform at the very top corresponds to three vertical slices
位于顶部的波形图分别对应着
of the record's first image,
这张唱片中的第一张图的三个垂直切片
while the zigzag pattern underneath
下面的锯齿状图案
means the slices are meant to be stacked side-by-side, one after the other.
表示这些切片要排成一排，彼此相邻
As we already know, this angelic symphony of beeps and buzzings
我们知道，这种“天使般”的哔哔和嗡嗡的节奏
are mapped to different shades of gray
被按照一种特定的转译方式
according to a very specific translation scheme.
对应到了不同的灰度上
A scheme the aliens are meant to reverse engineer
而外星人则需要根据这些二进制数字
with the help of these binary numbers.
来逆向出这种转译的方式
There are three slices labeled 1, 2, 3,
这三个切片标为 1、2、3
and each one corresponds to roughly 8 milliseconds of audio.
每一片对应这大概八毫秒的音频
A full image is 512 slices wide
一个完整的图像是 512 切片宽
and should form a rectangular shape with a 4:3 aspect ratio.
并且应该是一个 4:3 比例的矩形
Simple as that.
就像这样“简单”
On the off-chance that the aliens should somehow be
万一外星人因为某些原因
confused by these crystal clear instructions,
困于这些显而易见的指示
the record's first image has also been outlined here at the bottom
他们也可以在下面这里看到唱片的第一张图片的轮廓
to show them what it's supposed to look like when properly decoded.
从而知道这张图片正确解码后应该是什么样的
In fact, this calibration circle is the very first piece of data
实际上这个校准圆
the aliens would find on the record.
是外星人会在这张唱片上找到的第一组数据
It's followed by more than a hundred images, starting with some basic math,
它后面跟着的一百多张图片，以基础数学开头
units of measurement, and a speedrun of the human experience.
然后是计量单位，然后是人类经验的快速复盘
The sequence ends with this image of a violin floating above a page of musical notation.
最后是一张小提琴放在乐谱上的图像
It shows the beginning of a somber classical piece known as Cavatina,
它展示了一首庄严古典作品《卡瓦蒂娜》的开头
and once the image fades, legendary emcee Ludwig van Beethoven kicks off the mixtape.
在这张图片之后，传奇 MC 贝多芬就会开始播放混音磁带
But the minutes-long performance of Cavatina only plays for a few seconds
持续数分钟的《卡瓦蒂娜》只播放了几秒钟
before it's interrupted by even more beeps and buzzings.
随后就会被更多的哔哔声和嗡嗡声打断
You see, six additional images
你看，六张额外的图片
were squeezed onto the record at the very last moment,
被挤在唱片的最后一刻
including a written statement by then President of the United States, Jimmy Carter,
包括一份由时任美国总统吉米·卡特撰写的书面声明
and a tedious listing of nearly a hundred members of Congress.
以及一份包含一百名国会议员的无聊名单
This bureaucratic theme then segues back into audio
这份官僚主义的主题随后转入到音频
with a speech by then Secretary General of the United Nations, Kurt Waldheim.
这是一份来自时任联合国秘书长库尔特·瓦尔德海姆的致辞
The aliens will then be treated to a series of greetings
外星人然后会听到一些问候语
spoken in 58 different languages.
分别以 58 种不同的语言说出来
This is followed by various sounds of things like weather, animals, and technology
接下来是各种天气、动物和技术的声音
before the record ends with a playlist of nearly 90 minutes of music
最后是一组将近 90 分钟的音乐
covering a vast array of instruments, styles, and cultures.
其中涵盖各种乐器、风格和文化
It starts about halfway through the A side of the record
它从唱片 A 面的大概一半位置开始
with an uplifting composition by Johann Bach.
最开头是一首振奋的乐曲，由巴赫创作
After another nine tracks, including a famous American rock single and
另外九首曲目，包括一首著名的美国摇滚单曲
many obscure folk songs from around the world,
以及许多来自世界各地的隐秘民歌之后
the music picks up again on the record's B side with another banger by Johann Bach.
音乐在唱片的 B 面再次响起，又是以一首巴赫的著名曲目开头
After nearly an hour's worth of additional music from countries like
来自各个国家大约一个小时的音乐之后
Germany, Peru, Russia, China, and India, just to name a few,
包括德国、秘鲁、俄罗斯、中国、印度，等等
the Golden Record comes to a somnific end with a full rendition of Beethoven's Cavatina
黄金唱片的最后呈现了贝多芬的《卡瓦蒂娜》的完整版，十分助眠
Nearly half a century later,
大约半个世纪后
Voyager 1 is now the most distant spacecraft ever launched.
旅行者一号是目前发射过最远的航天器
Even though it was preceded by the Pioneer probes by several years
尽管先驱者探测器还要比它早几年
and even its own twin by two weeks,
尽管它的双胞胎兄弟比它早了两个星期
Voyager 1 attained a greater escape velocity and has since overtaken them all.
旅行者一号获得了更大的逃逸速度，之后就超越了他们
Amazingly, both Voyagers are still transmitting to this day,
令人难以置信的是，两位旅行者至今仍在发射信号
although they're fast approaching their operational limits.
尽管他们很快就要超出运行范围
Once they go offline and fall out of range,
一旦他们断线并超出范围
they'll join their pioneering brethren
他们也将和他们的先驱兄弟一样
in a timeless and destinationless trek between the stars.
踏上星际间永恒而无目标的旅程
Because the interstellar medium is sparsely populated with tiny dust particles,
由于星际之间稀疏分布着微小的尘埃颗粒
the exposed surfaces of both the Pioneer Plaques
两块先驱者镀金铝板
and the Golden Records will erode over time.
和黄金唱片都会随着时间的推移而老化
While the former is somewhat protected by its inward-facing placement,
虽然前者由于朝内摆放，有一定的保护作用
it's still exposed to the vacuum of space.
它仍然暴露在太空的真空中
On the other hand, the Golden Records are
另一方面，黄金唱片
firmly pressed up against the body of the spacecraft.
牢固地贴靠在飞船身上
According to one estimate, the outward-facing B side
据估计，朝外的 B 面
could survive for at least a few billion years,
可以至少维持数十亿年
whereas the lifespan of the concealed A side is anyone's guess.
而被盖上的 A 面的寿命就说不定了
It's not impossible that many tens or even hundreds of billions of years from now,
也许在数百亿甚至数千亿年后，
all the photographs, greetings, and one third of the music will still be intact.
所有的照片、问候语以及三分之一的音乐仍将完好无损
While the response to the Golden Records was overwhelmingly positive,
虽然群众对黄金唱片的反应相当正面
they did nonetheless receive a bit of criticism.
他们仍然收到了一些批评
Much like before, some people were completely undeterred
和之前一样，一部分人依然坚信
by the near-impossibility of interception
这些东西会被截获，虽然几乎是不可能的
and feared the Voyagers might attract a hostile intelligence.
因而他们担心旅行者会引来敌对的智慧生物
Others focused more on the contents of the message
其他人更关注消息传递的内容
because they felt it was disingenuous to paint humanity in such a positive light
他们觉得给人性投射如此正面的光芒是不诚实的
when war, crime, and cruelty
战争、犯罪、残忍的行为
are as much a part of the human condition as music, sports, and science.
如同音乐、体育和科学，都是人类现状的一部分
As one of the makers of the record, Jon Lomberg, so succinctly points out...
正如唱片的制作人之一，乔恩·隆伯格言简意赅地指出...
The decision to exclude the uglier sides of humanity was
之所以决定排除人性中的丑陋一面
partly to avoid potential backlash from people here on Earth,
部分是为了避免这地球上的人的抵制
but also an attempt to make us seem less hostile to any future recipients.
同时也为了让我们在未来的接收者那里看来不那么有敌意
While a mushroom cloud does convey a
诚然，蘑菇云的确传达了
shameful yet significant part of who we are,
我们可耻但又重要的一面
it could also be perceived as a threat.
但这也可能会被视为一种威胁
On the other hand, the exclusion of such imagery
另一方面，排除人类这种形象的行为本身
could, by itself, be quite revealing
已经能说明很多问题
as we expose our casual willingness to deceive
因为我们以一种巧妙的省略行为
through tactful omission.
展现出了一种肆意的欺骗习惯
Dating profiles, job interviews, meeting someone for the first time.
就像约会软件的个人资料，工作面试，初次见面
I don't know if this is what the Golden Records team had in mind, but
我不确定这是否就是黄金唱片团队所想营造的
being selective with the truth to make a good first impression,
但选择性地面对真相以给人留下好印象
how terribly human of them.
他们这样做真的是非常“人类”了
The three initiatives mentioned so far
我们目前所提到的三个计划
are likely to be the only ones you've heard of before.
或许就涵盖了你所知道的全部
The Pioneer Plaques, the Arecibo Message, and especially the Golden Records
先驱者镀金铝板，阿雷西博信息，尤其是黄金唱片
generated immense public interest at the time and remain well known to this day.
它们都在当时引起了巨大的公众兴趣，至今仍然广为人知
But our attempts to communicate with life beyond
但我们与超越生命沟通的尝试
did not end with the Golden Records.
并没有止于黄金唱片
In fact, just a few years later, the silence was broken yet again,
实际上几年之后，沉寂再度被打破
and this time, the target was so close,
这一次我们的目标非常接近
the minimum response time was measured not in eons
预计的最短回复时间不在千万年
but decades.
而在短短几十年
In early 1983, Japanese publishing company Shueisha
1983 年初，日本出版公司集英社
was looking for ways to commemorate the 15th anniversary
正在考虑十五周年纪念的形式
of their most popular manga anthology magazine,
这是为了纪念他们最火爆的漫画选集杂志
known as Weekly Shnen Jump.
《周刊少年 Jump》
Due to the recent success of the film E.T. by Steven Spielberg,
由于史蒂文·斯皮尔伯格的电影《外星人》的成功
and the fact that 1983 had been declared the World Communications Year
并且那一年被联合国定为
by the United Nations,
世界传播年
they decided to launch a competition dubbed Call to the Cosmos.
他们决定推出一项名为“呼叫宇宙”的比赛
The price was a trip across the Pacific
比赛的奖励是一次旅行，可横跨太平洋
to visit a large radio telescope in Stanford, California,
前往参观加利福尼亚州斯坦福的一台大型射电望远镜
from which a message would be transmitted
这也是向附近的恒星系统
to a nearby star system.
发射信息的地方
To win, all you had to do was submit a proposal for what the message should say.
要赢得奖励，你只需要提交一份关于信息内容的提案
With a readership in the millions, the magazine received
坐拥百万读者，杂志收到了
nearly 50 000 message ideas from children across the country.
将近五万条来自全国各地的儿童的留言创意
These were then compiled into one abbreviated message,
这些创意被汇编成一个简短的留言
and 15 lucky winners were selected to tag along on the trip.
并抽取了十五个幸运儿一同踏上奖励之旅
For the selection of a transmission target,
为了选定发送的目标
the organizers turned to two radio astronomers
组织者咨询了两位射电天文学家
named Masaki Morimoto and Hisashi Hirabayashi.
森本雅树和平林久
They eventually chose the star Altair
他们最终选择了牛郎星
because it's very bright and relatively close.
一个原因是这颗星很明亮且相对较近
It was also selected because the message was planned to be transmitted
还因为这条消息计划于
during an annual Japanese festival known as Tanabata
一年一度的七夕节发射
which celebrates the meeting of two celestial deities
这一节日是庆祝两位天神的相遇
represented by the stars Vega and Altair.
它们分别由织女星和牛郎星来代表
Furthermore, Morimoto and Hirabayashi were asked to create their own message,
此外，森本和平林也要创作他们自己的信息
and after three days of work, they came up with this.
经过三天的工作，他们想出了这些
A sequence of 13 bitmaps measuring 71x71 pixels
一组共十三个位图，每幅图尺寸为 71x71 像素
that were clearly inspired by the Arecibo Message.
很显然受到了阿雷西博信息的启发
The first four images depict things like natural numbers,
前四张图描绘了自然数
prime numbers, basic math, common elements,
质数、基础数学、常见化学元素
the Solar System,
太阳系
and essential building blocks of DNA.
DNA 的基本组成部分
The next eight illustrate the evolution of life
接下来的八个描绘了生物的进化史
from simple organisms to jellyfish,
从简单有机体到水母
fish,
鱼
amphibians,
两栖动物
dinosaurs,
恐龙
apparently not Bigfoot,
显然不是大脚怪的东西
a family of humans,
一个人类家庭
and a close-up of a woman's face.
以及一位女士脸部的特写
The final bitmap depicts a crude illustration
最后的这张位图展示的是
of the Stanford radio telescope
斯坦福射电望远镜的一个粗略图示
alongside information like its radius, wavelength of the transmission,
旁边放着它的半径、发射的波长等信息
and total number of bits in the message.
以及信息的总比特数
We also find the word "TOAST" written in plain English.
我们还会发现用英文写着的“干杯”一词
According to Hirabayashi, during the three-day stint
根据平林的说法，在三天的时间里
when he and Morimoto conceived of these images,
他和森本在想这些图片的时候
they weren't necessarily sober the whole way through.
不是一直都清醒着
This may or may not have influenced their decision to include
这或许影响了他们决定
the Japanese and English word for "TOAST"
将日语和英语中的“干杯”
equated to the chemical formula for ethanol.
与酒精的化学式联系起来
Because Weekly Shnen Jump targets a very young demographic,
由于《周刊少年 Jump》的受众非常年轻
the magazine tried to clean this up a bit
杂志尝试过对此做出澄清
by reframing what was clearly an afterthought
它们尝试将这种明显是两个半醉的天文学家
by two half-drunk astronomers as...
所做出的东西解释为...
Nevertheless, for about an hour on August 15, 1983,
在 1983 年 8 月 15 日的大约一个小时内，
the 13 bitmaps and an audio recording of the abridged fan-submitted greetings
13 张位图和一份粉丝提供的简略问候语录音
were beamed towards Altair.
向着牛郎星发射了出去
Altair is among the brightest stars in the night sky,
牛郎星是夜空中最亮的星之一
and at a distance of less than 17 lightyears,
距离地球不到 17 光年
it's only, what, a few quadrillion stone throws away?
这只不过是... 大概几万亿次？往池塘里丢石头中的一次
In fact, Altair is so cosmically close that enough time has now passed
实际上，牛郎星在宇宙尺度上离我们非常近，到现在经过的时间
for the transmission to have made a full round trip.
已经足够让信号完成一次往返了
That is to say, the message reached Altair back around the millennium shift,
也就是说，那条信息在千禧年的时候就到达了河鼓二
and we could have received a reply as early as 2017.
我们也应早在 2017 年就收到回复
Now, the fact that we never did does not necessarily mean there's nobody home.
到现在我们还没有收到回复，也并不意味着那里没有人
Perhaps they missed the brief 60-minute window
或许是他们错过了消息掠过他们系统的
when the message swept across their system?
60 分钟窗口期？
Perhaps they did pick it up, but they're still drafting a response?
或许他们的确收到了，但仍然在拟定回复的内容？
Perhaps they took one quick look at Earth and humanity, and were like...
或许他们只是快速地看了看地球和人类，然后...
While all of these scenarios are, of course, equally probable,
虽然后面列出的这些情况都有同样的可能
the most equal is, unfortunately, the first one.
但不幸的是，第一种情况最有可能
Not only have astronomers failed to detect a planet around Altair, but
天文学家不仅找不到牛郎星附近的行星
even if one does exist, the star's only been around for about 100 million years.
即使的确存在行星，牛郎星也只存在了十亿年
Compare that to a 4.6 billion-year veteran like the Sun,
将其与像太阳这样四十六亿年的老资历相比
and things start to look a bit bleak.
事情就显得有些无望了
Sure, there's always the possibility that intelligent life
当然，总有可能那里的智慧生命
typically evolves much faster than it did here on Earth,
比在地球上的进化速度要快
but we currently have no good reason to think that's the case.
但我们目前没有充分的理由这么想
But it gets worse because even if the Altairians did respond,
更严重的是，如果牛郎人确实给出了回复
the odds of us even noticing are extremely remote
我们注意到这些的可能性也极低
because telescopes are expensive, in low supply, and high demand.
因为我们的望远镜昂贵、稀缺且有高需求
Sacrificing years, months, or even just days worth of observation time
牺牲数年、数月甚至仅仅几天的观察时间
to screen a single planetless star for alien signals ain't exactly top priority.
去扫描一个没有行星的恒星的外星信号并不是很重要
It wasn't until the summer of 2023
一直到 2023 年的夏天
that a team led by astronomer Shin-ya Narusawa
由天文学家鸣泽真也领导的团队
secured a brief time slot at the Usuda Deep Space Center in Japan
才在位于日本的臼田宇宙电波观测所获得短暂的时间
to search for a belated response to the Altair Message.
来搜索对牛郎星信息迟来的回复
Scheduled once again to coincide with the annual Tanabata festival,
这次活动被再次安排在一年一度的七夕节期间进行
the search began late in the evening on August 22
搜索开始于八月二十二日的深夜
and lasted for a grand total of 60...
并且总共持续了 60...
...minutes.
...分钟
Remaining optimistic, Narusawa told reporters the following morning
次日早上，仍然乐观的鸣泽告诉记者
that they wouldn't immediately know if an alien signal had been detected
他们不会马上就知道外星信号是否真的被探测到了
because it would take a long time to analyze the terabytes of collected data.
因为分析收集到的 TB 级数据就需要很长的时间
But given the lack of updates since then, I wouldn't keep my hopes up on this one.
但鉴于在那之后就没什么消息了，我不会对此抱有太大的希望
If nothing else, the Message to Altair was received loud and clear
至少，发给牛郎星的信息
by thousands of children across Japan.
已经被全日本数千名儿童清晰地接收到了
In fact, Call to the Cosmos seems to have had a bit of a rippling effect
实际上，“呼叫宇宙”似乎产生了一些连锁反应
because a whole series of messages designed by Japanese children
因为在之后的几年里
would later be transmitted for several years in a row.
由日本儿童设计的一系列信息被持续传播开来
But before we get to all that,
但说这些之前
we're gonna take a brief detour into the dazzling world of censorship.
我们先在言论审查的花花世界里兜转一圈
As mentioned before, when the public became aware
如前所述，当公众意识到
that NASA had bolted a plaque to the side of Pioneer 10, not everyone approved.
NASA 将一块铭牌固定在先驱者十号飞船的侧面时，并不是所有人都赞同
But it wasn't just about the risk of attracting dangerous aliens.
这不仅仅关乎吸引危险外星人的风险
It was also about modesty.
这还关乎“贤淑”
You see, some people were absolutely mortified
你看，有些人简直不敢相信
to learn that the plaques featured line drawings of two naked humans
铭牌上有着两个赤裸人体的线条画
engaged in the scandalous act of standing there.
而他们就那样可耻地站在那里
As amusing as that is, the controversy surrounding the plaques' nudity
这的确很搞笑，但关于镀金铝板上裸体的争议环境
has been somewhat exaggerated over the years.
在过去几年的时间里有些被夸大了
These puritanical takes were "muted and few", to quote Carl Sagan,
用卡尔·萨根的话来说，这些清教徒式的观点“微弱且少见”
and it's genuinely difficult to find examples like the one you just heard.
要找到像你刚才听到那个例子其实很难
There were a handful of reductive headlines,
有一些文章的标题过于简化
and some newspapers opted for the Barbie- and Ken-doll treatment, but
一些报纸选择了芭比娃娃式和肯娃娃式的处理方式，但是
the vast majority published the full uncensored image and
但大部分都发布了完整的未打码图片
barely even mentioned the couple.
甚至几乎没有提到那对夫妇
In fact, some criticized the plaques not for showing the human form,
一些人并不是因其展现人体而批判镀金铝板
but for not showing enough.
而是因为其展现得不够充分
More specifically, people took issue with the complete
更确切地说，这些人不满于
absence of visible female genitalia,
图上没有可见的女性生殖器
considering that no such neutering had been applied to the man.
因为他们发现一旁的男人就没有被这样“阉割”
It's unclear if the lack of anatomical detail on the lower half of the woman
这个女人的下半身缺少解剖学细节
was demanded by prudish NASA officials, or a decision made by the Sagans themselves.
并不清楚是保守 NASA 官员的要求，还是萨根夫妇所做的决定
Conflicting accounts makes it difficult to know exactly who's to blame.
相互矛盾的各种说法，使得很难确定到底谁该负责
Nevertheless, when it came time to select material
到了几年后
for the Golden Records a few years later,
给黄金唱片挑选材料的时候
these concerns flared up again.
这些担忧再次出现
Fearing a repeat of the previous debacle,
由于担心之前的问题重演
NASA religiously vetted every song, soundbite, and image
NASA 严格审查了萨根及其合作者选中的
that Sagan and co sought to include.
每一首歌、音节和图像
They ultimately rejected a nude photograph
他们最后拒绝了一张裸体照片
of a young man and pregnant woman
其中包含了一个年轻的男人和怀孕的女人
intended to show both human anatomy and procreation.
这旨在展示人体的解剖学和生殖结构
The reason I'm bringing this up is because, in 1986,
我提出这一茬的原因是，1986 年，
an American artist by the name of Joe Davis
一位名叫乔·戴维斯的美国艺术家
decided to fight back against all this pearl-clutching
决定用他的一个名为阴道之诗的作品
with a project known as Poetica Vaginal.
来反击所有的过分指责
With the help of a few ballerinas and other volunteers,
在几个芭蕾舞演员和志愿者的帮助下
Davis used a custom-made device to record...
戴维斯使用了一台定制设备来录制...
...how do I put this...
...我该怎么说呢...
...contractions from within the female reproductive system.
...来自女性生殖系统的收缩
Those pressure oscillations were then artistically manipulated
这些压力引起的震荡经过艺术加工
to create something that's meant to resemble human speech.
变成了某种类似于人类发言的声音
After obtaining access to a radio telescope
在获得麻省理工学院附近
near the Massachusetts Institute of Technology,
射电望远镜的访问权限后
Davis and his team began transmitting the sounds into space.
戴维斯和他的团队开始向太空传输这些声音
However, the broadcast only lasted for about 15 to 20 minutes
然而，该广播只持续了大约 15 到 20 分钟
before the project was prematurely terminated by an Air Force Colonel,
之后就被一位空军上校提前叫停
who was apparently overseeing the facility.
显然他是当时设施的看守者
Nevertheless, according to Davis,
无论如何，根据戴维斯的说法
those few minutes were enough to transmit brief snippets of audio
这短短几分钟已经足以向四个选定的目标
to each of the four selected targets.
传输一些简短的音频片段
Two of them were never publicly identified, as far as I can tell,
据我所知，其中的两个目标从未被公开说明过
while the other two are known as Epsilon Eridani and Tau Ceti.
另外两个则是天苑四和天仓五
Epsilon Eridani is home to one confirmed planet
天苑四已经确认有一个行星
with a mass nearly identical to that of Jupiter.
其质量几乎与木星的相同
While additional planets could exist,
虽然可能存在其他行星
including ones that resemble Earth,
包括像地球这样的
Eridani is a relative newcomer to the Milky Way family
但天苑四只是银河系的一个相对新的成员
at approximately half a billion years young.
它大概有五亿岁
On the other hand, Tau Ceti is certifiably ancient.
另一边，天仓五是货真价实的古老
Its precise age remains unclear, but it's definitely older than the Sun
它确切的年龄尚不明确，但绝对比太阳更老
and home to not just one, but four confirmed planets.
并且它有不止一个，而是四个确认的行星
On top of that, there's a slim chance that two of them
以及，其中的两个行星有微小的可能
are grazing the inner and outer bounds of the habitable zone.
恰好与宜居带的内外边界擦肩而过
That being the distance from the star
也就是与恒星的距离
at which water could remain liquid on the surface of an earthlike planet.
使得类地行星表面上的水可以维持在液态
Unfortunately, both of these stars are surrounded by immense belts of debris,
不幸的是，这两个恒星都被巨大的带状碎片环绕着
not unlike the Asteroid and Kuiper belts in the Solar System.
与太阳系中的小行星带和柯伊伯带类似
The difference is that Epsilon Eridani and Tau Ceti
差别在于，天苑四和天仓五
retain asteroidal and cometary populations
具有相当多的小行星和彗星群
many times greater than what currently orbits the Sun.
比当前绕着太阳转的还多很多倍
While this makes perfect sense for a youngster like Eridani,
这对于像天苑四这样的年轻恒星来说非常合理
it's a lot more concerning for a galactic grandparent like Tau Ceti.
但对于像天仓五这样的星际老爷来说就有些令人担忧了
It implies that something is either preventing that material from
这可能暗示着有些东西要么使得物质
coalescing into planets across billions of years
在数十亿年间无法聚合成行星
or that the system has suffered a recent cascade of instability.
要么这一系统最近遭受了一系列不稳定事件
In either case, more stuff almost certainly means more impact events
无论哪种情况，碎片越多，碰撞事件可以说就越多
like the one that nearly wiped out the dinosaurs.
就像灭绝了恐龙的那种碰撞一样
But even if we optimistically assume that none of that's a problem,
即使我们乐观地认为这些都不是问题
the mass and size of the planets orbiting Tau Ceti are highly uncertain.
围绕天仓五运转的行星的质量和大小都很不确定
There's a good chance they have less in common with Earth
它们大概率和地球的共同点更少
and more so with Uranus and Neptune.
而与天王星和海王星则更多
But even if that isn't the case,
就算不这样
the chemical makeup of Tau Ceti appears to be quite different from the Sun,
天仓五的化学组成似乎也与太阳的相当不同
suggesting its planets are composed of materials
这表示其行星是由不同于
quite different from those that spawned life in the Solar System.
在太阳系中孕育了生命的那些物质所构成的
In summary, it's not looking great.
总而言之，情况不容乐观
Now, it may seem pointless to consider the habitability of these distant worlds
如果我们给他们发送的信息完全无法解密
when the message we sent towards them is completely indecipherable.
考虑这些遥远世界的宜居性似乎就毫无意义
I mean, if you thought the aliens were gonna struggle with the Golden Records,
我说，如果外星人真的会去纠结金唱片传达了些什么的话
good luck to them figuring this out.
就祝他们能看懂这东西吧——
But just like the Arecibo Message, the artificial nature of the signal
就像阿雷西博信息那样，信号的人造性
is a message in and of itself.
本身就是一条信息
If you want to believe there's a naturally occurring phenomenon
如果你相信存在一种自然现象
capable of producing the exact same radio waves
能够产生与乔·戴维斯和他的团队在 1986 年发出的
as those emitted by Joe Davis and his team back in 1986,
完全相同的无线电波
you go right ahead.
那就随便你吧
But somehow, I have my doubts about that.
可是，我对这件事有一些怀疑
Presuming the message was received and correctly identified as a technosignature,
假设这条消息已经被收到且被正确认定为是一种技术签名
we could've received a reply from the Eridanians as early as 2007
我们可能早在 2007 年就收到来自天苑四人的回复
or the Cetinites as early as 2010.
或者在 2010 年就收到来自天仓五人的回复
I did some checking and regretfully have to inform you
我做了一些调查，只能很遗憾的告诉你
that humanity's been ghosted once again.
人类又被忽略了
About a decade after the Message to Altair,
大约在向牛郎星发送消息的十年后
the National Space Development Agency of Japan
日本的宇宙开发事业团
began hosting an annual space camp event for young children
开始举办一年一度的青少年太空营活动
known as the Cosmic College.
这被称为宇宙学院
Students could choose from a bunch of different activities
学生可以在这几天里
over the course of multiple days,
选择许多不同的活动
including a class on how to write and send interstellar messages.
包括一个教你编写和发送星际信息课程
In fact, one of the astronomers invited to lecture at these events
事实上，有一位天文学家被邀请到这些活动中发表演讲
was none other than Hisashi Hirabayashi, one of the creators of the Altair Message.
不是别人，正是平林久，牛郎星信息的创造者之一
But it wasn't just a theoretical exercise.
这些课程不仅限于理论
NASDA actually arranged for some of those messages to be transmitted into space.
宇宙开发事业团实际上把一部分信息真的发送到了太空
Once a year between at least 1995 and 1998,
至少在 1995 年至 1998 年期间，每年都会有一次
simple bitmap images measuring 11x11 pixels
一系列 11x11 像素的简单位图图像
were sent from the Usuda Deep Space Center to various locations across the galaxy.
从臼田深空中心发向银河系的多个地点
These transmissions received next to no publicity at the time
这些传输在当时几乎没有引起任何关注
and are virtually unknown to this day.
至今也是鲜为人知
This makes it difficult to know exactly what was sent where and when.
这使得我们很难知道在哪里什么时候发送了什么
Here's what we do know.
下面是一些我们可以掌握的信息
The first Cosmic College was held in August 1995,
首届宇宙学院在 1995 年 8 月举行
during which this image of two parents and a child
期间，这一张父母与孩子的照片
was beamed towards some unknown destination within the constellation Libra.
被射向天秤座中的某处不明地点
Even less is known about this image of an alien holding hands with a human,
这张人类与外星人握手的图片，则更鲜为人知
transmitted sometime in August 1996.
它是在 1996 年 8 月发送的
This time, we don't even know the general region of the sky
这次我们甚至不知道
to which it might have been sent.
它是向天空中的哪片区域发送的
In August 1997, two bitmaps were beamed towards a binary star system known as Spica.
1997 年 8 月，这两张位图被发射到名为角宿一的联星
The first image depicts a smiley face,
第一张图展示了一个笑脸
while the other shows a Japanese dumpling known as a dango
另一张图展示了一种日本的饺子，名为团子
next to a steaming cup of tea.
放在一杯冒着热气的茶旁边
Unfortunately, Spica is a ticking time bomb
不幸的是，角宿一是一颗定时炸弹
because the two stars are expected to slowly encroach upon one another,
因为这两颗恒星会慢慢地互相侵蚀
which could trigger a supernova at some point in the future.
这可能会在将来某个时间点引起超新星爆发
Even if that wasn't the case, they're far too young to host an earthlike planet,
就算不爆发，它们的存在时间也不足以形成一颗类地行星
and even if that wasn't the case, it would take another five centuries for
就算真的形成了，还需要五百年
any replies to reach us.
我们才可能收到回复
Finally, this image that simply says 1 + 1 = 2
最后的这张图片上只有简单的 1+1=2
was transmitted to some unknown location in August 1998.
在 1998 年 8 月被发送到某个未知的地点
Now, there could be more of these transmissions that have been lost to time.
可能还有更多被时间掩埋的发送行动
For instance, an image of a leaf to symbolize the nature of Earth
例如，有一张用来表示地球上大自然的叶子图片
appears to have been designed during the Cosmic College of 1999.
似乎是在 1999 年的太空学院期间被设计出来的
But I couldn't find any information on whether it was actually beamed into space.
但我找不到关于它的任何信息，也不知道它有没有真的被发送
While competitions, art projects, and recreational programs
虽然比赛、艺术项目和休闲项目
certainly could generate an alien response,
确实有可能引起外星人的反应
their primary function is to elicit a response from us down here on Earth.
但它们的主要功能还是引起我们地球人的反应
They're inspiring, provocative, and generally attract a lot of attention.
它们鼓舞人心、引人深思，而且通常都能吸引大量关注
So it was only a matter of time before someone came along
所以早晚会有人来专门收钱
and began charging a fee.
这只是时间问题
In early 1998, American entrepreneur Charles Chafer
1998 年初，美国企业家查尔斯·查弗
announced a commercial venture known as Encounter 2001.
宣布了一个商业项目，名为“相遇 2001”
The project sought to crowdfund the launch of a tiny light-sailing spacecraft
该项目旨在通过众筹来发射一艘小型航天飞船
that wouldcarry samples of human DNA beyond the Solar System.
它将携带人类 DNA 样本穿越太阳系
For only $50, anyone could submit a few strands of hair
只需 50 美元，任何人都可以提交自己的几根头发
along with a brief message and their portrait
以及一条简短信息，和他们的大头照
and join the so-called Millennial Voyage.
从而加入所谓的千禧航行
Market analysis by Chafer and his team
查弗和他的团队进行的市场分析
projected sales of anywhere between 1.5 and 4.5 million tickets
估计在发射日期之前
before the launch date.
销售额在 150 万到 450 万张门票之间
If those figures seem a bit optimistic,
这数字看起来有点乐观
they were nothing compared to the expectations of their customers.
但与他们客户的期望相比，简直微不足道
This idea that aliens might one day use your DNA to clone your body
外星人某天可能会用你的 DNA 来克隆你的身体的想法
was surprisingly prevalent.
出乎意料的火爆
For instance, the greeting submitted
例如，由著名科幻小说作家
by renowned science fiction author Sir Arthur C. Clarke
亚瑟·查尔斯·克拉克所提交的问候语
simply read, "Fare well, my clone!"
只有一句话：“别了，我的克隆体！”
While the Millennial Voyage was the project's main objective,
虽然千禧航行是这个项目的主要目标
they also promised to beam participants' greetings into space ahead of the launch
他们还承诺在发射飞船之前，用射电望远镜把参与者的问候语
using a radio telescope.
发射到太空中去
A side project that would come to be known as the Cosmic Calls.
这是一个被称为“宇宙呼叫”的次级项目
By spring of 1999, some 43 000 people had signed up for Encounter 2001,
截至 1999 年春，已有约 43000 人报名参加相遇 2001
including two Canadian astrophysicists named Yvan Dutil and Stphane Dumas.
包括两位加拿大天体物理学家，伊万·杜提尔和斯特凡·杜马斯
Dutil and Dumas had been given the task of creating what's known as a primer.
杜提尔和杜马斯有编写“引导”的任务在身
A primer attempts to gradually introduce the recipients to more complex ideas
引导的一大目的是用某种分步的方式向接收者
using some sort of step-by-step process.
引出一些更复杂的概念
For instance, the primer of the Message to Altair
例如，牛郎星信息的引导
were the 13 bitmaps sent alongside the far more complicated greeting in Japanese.
就是与更复杂的日语问候一同发送的十三张位图
Dutil and Dumas did something similar for the Cosmic Calls.
杜提尔和杜马斯为宇宙呼叫做了一些类似的准备
They created a primer composed of 23 bitmaps,
他们创建了由二十三张位图构成的引导
and this first one starts off by listing the ten digits of our decimal system
第一张列出了我们十进制系统中的十个数字
using three different notations: unary, binary, and decimal.
并以三种记号来呈现：一元、二元和十进制
An idea they appear to have lifted from this image on the Golden Records,
他们似乎是从金唱片上的这张图片中借鉴的这个想法
which did almost the exact same thing.
他们的这张图几乎做了完全相同的事情
But there is, of course, one very noticeable difference.
当然，有一个十分明显的差异
The one from the Golden Records uses the familiar glyphs of Arabic numerals,
黄金唱片上的使用了我们熟悉的阿拉伯数字符号
whereas the primer to the Cosmic Calls uses these alien-looking symbols.
而这个宇宙呼叫的引导则使用了一些外星符号
That's because Dutil and Dumas decided to create their own
这是因为杜提尔和杜马斯决定创建他们自己的
rudimentary language of sorts.
一种简易的语言
Now, this might seem like an odd choice
现在这可能是一个奇怪的决定
because whether, say, a two, looks like this or like this,
因为无论，比如，数字二，是像这样还是像这样
it's not gonna make any difference to the recipients.
对接收者来说并没有很大差别
But it's not about readability. It's about redundancy.
但这与可读性关系不大，而是冗余的考虑
You see, there's a lot of naturally occurring radiation that could
有大量的自然辐射可能
interfere with a radio transmission between the source and destination.
干扰源地和目的地之间的无线电传输
Imagine, for instance, that we transmitted fifteen bits arranged like this
假设我们将这样排列的十五个位传输出去
to represent the number 8.
来表示数字八
If this one bit in the middle was flipped along the way,
如果中间的这一位在中途被翻转
the recipients would pick up a 0 instead of an 8.
接收者会得到零而不是八
Flip this bit, and the 8 becomes a 6.
把这个位翻转一下，八就会变成六
Flip these two, and it becomes a 5.
把这两个位都翻一下，就变成了五
In other words, this transmission has no redundancy whatsoever.
换句话说，这种传输没有任何的冗余考虑
Lose one bit and the entire message could become corrupted.
只要丢掉一位，整个消息都会损坏
The glyphs created by Dutil and Dumas were designed to be as
杜提尔和杜马斯所设计的这些字符
fault-tolerant and noise-resistant as possible.
尽可能地提高了容错率和抗噪声的程度
There are several bits of difference between all the symbols,
所有的符号之间都有几个位的差异
and that still holds true even if they were to be mirrored or rotated.
即使在镜像或者旋转以后，也是如此
But apart from the symbolic difference,
除了这种符号上的差异
the Cosmic Call primer follows a structure that should be very familiar at this point.
这一宇宙呼叫的引导遵循了一种我们现在会很熟悉的结构
The first five pages cover various mathematical concepts that
前五页会介绍一些数学的概念
gradually increase in complexity.
复杂度逐渐提高
The next six delve into chemistry and physics,
接下来的六页则深入化学和物理
including a schematic of the Solar System.
并包含一张太阳系的示意图
The next eight are all about Earth, humanity, and biology,
接下来八页是关于地球、人类和生物
including a rendition of the Pioneer couple and a two-page map of the continents.
包括一张镀金铝板上男女的图像和两页的大陆地图
Page 21 contains information about the transmission and telescope,
第二十一页包含信息传输和望远镜的信息
while page 22 brags about our cosmological knowledge, like the age of the universe.
第二十二页则炫耀了我们的宇宙知识，比如我们知道的宇宙年龄
The 23rd and final page invites the aliens to respond
第二十三页也是最后一页，邀请外星人进行回复
by asking them a series of questions,
这里向它们提出一系列的问题
using this flower-looking glyph as a stand-in for a question mark.
这个像花的符号代替了问号
For instance, this means velocity while this means photon,
例如，这个表示速度，这个表示光子
so this question could be read as, "What is the speed of light?"
所以这个问题可以理解为“光的速度是多少？”
But how could the aliens possibly know
但外星人怎么可能
that these symbols mean question, velocity, and photon?
知道这些符号表示着一个问题、速度以及光子呢？
Well, it all comes down to that first page of numbers
嗯...这都来自于第一页的那一堆数字
to which everything else is anchored.
这是之后一切的参考
The aliens would start by hypothesizing that these ten symbols
外星人会首先假设这十个符号
represent ten digits in a base-ten numeral system.
代表着一个十进制数字系统中的十个数位
With that assumption locked in place,
带着这个假设
they'd move on to the next page and find 1 something 1 = 2.
他们翻到下一页就会发现“一什么一等于二”
Okay, so they now suspect that this symbol represents addition
现在他们会推测这个符号表示加法
and make similar assumptions regarding subtraction, multiplication, and division.
然后做出一些类似的假设来推断出减法、乘法和除法
Once they get to page four, they would know that this reads something + 2 = 3,
到了第四页后，他们就会知道这是“什么加二等于三”
while this reads something + 4 = 10.
这是“什么加四等于十”
Given that the same symbol
发现相同的符号
is used to represent what is clearly not the same value,
被用来表示很明显不相同的值
they might suspect that this is a placeholder for a variable quantity.
他们可能就会认为这是一个用来表示可变数量的占位符
In other words, this variable represents something unknown,
或者说，这个变量是用来表示某种未知的东西
a bit like a question mark, emphasized by this symbol off to the left.
有点像问号，由左边的这个符号强调
By gradually introducing new symbols alongside familiar ones
通过在已知符号基础上引入新的符号
in such a way that logic and process of elimination
以这种方式，就可以通过逻辑推理和排除法
can be used to fill in the blanks,
来填补空缺
it creates a lot of mutual corroboration between the pages.
从而在不同的页面之间创造相互佐证的联系
By page eight, they'd be introduced to the concepts of time and length via hydrogen,
在第八页，他们会通过氢元素了解到时间和长度的概念
followed by velocity and photons via the speed of light.
通过光速来了解速度和光子的概念
To be clear, there's still plenty of room for confusion and misinterpretation.
确切地说，其实他们仍有可能产生疑问甚至误读
Not least of all because a few typos did actually slip through the cracks.
其中一个重要原因是，确实有些拼写错误漏网了
For instance, according to this line on the seventh page,
例如，根据第七页上的这一行文字
uranium is said to have 116 neutrons but there is no such element.
称铀元素有 116 个中子，但不存在这样的元素
The lightest known isotope of uranium has 122 neutrons
铀元素最轻的同位素也有 122 个中子
and the most abundant here on Earth has 146
而在地球上最丰富的同位素则有 146 个中子
which is probably what they meant.
很可能他们想说的是 146
But even if the primer had been flawless,
就算这篇引导中不存在瑕疵
there's only so much hand-holding one can do
作为一个有手的人，你也只能做这么多了
when you don't even know if the recipients have hands.
你甚至不确定接收者是不是真的有手
In addition to the primer, the language created by Dutil and Dumas
除了这篇引导之外，杜提尔和杜马斯创造的那门语言
was used to write a message about the Millennial Voyage.
被用于编写一段关于千禧航行的信息
This was followed by a copy of the Arecibo Message,
随后是阿雷西博信息的一个副本
greetings by the staff at Encounter 2001,
然后是相遇 2001 工作人员的问候
as well as the 43 000 names and greetings from people around the world.
最后是世界各地的四万三千个人的姓名和他们的问候
With assistance from prominent Russian astronomer Alexander Zaitsev,
在著名俄罗斯天文学家亚历山大·扎伊采夫的帮助下
Chafer and his team then obtained access to the
查弗和他的团队得以访问
Evpatoria Deep Space Center in southern Ukraine,
乌克兰南部的叶夫帕托里亚深空中心
and the first Cosmic Call began broadcasting on May 24, 1999.
于是第一次宇宙呼叫在 1999 年 5 月 24 日被广播出去
Unlike many other initiatives,
与其他的计划不同
which received very little attention from the press and public,
其他的计划都没有受到媒体和公众的多少关注
the Cosmic Calls were a global phenomenon.
而宇宙呼叫却在全球流行
In fact, the project received so much attention
事实上，该项目引起了极大关注
that officials at the National Space Agency of Ukraine
以至于乌克兰国家航天局的官员们有些紧张
got a bit spooked.
感到不安
The plan was to beam the message to four nearby star systems,
原计划是向四个邻近的恒星系统发送这条信息
but after the first transmission on May 24,
但在五月二十四日的首次发射之后
Ukrainian officials suddenly shut the whole thing down.
乌克兰官员突然叫停了整个项目
According to Zaitsev, rumors had begun circulating
根据扎伊采夫的说法，有传闻说
that the reason Encounter 2001 were using the Evpatoria Deep Space Center
相遇 2001 之所以会来找叶夫帕托里亚深空中心
was because they'd been denied access to American facilities
是因为他们被美国的设施拒绝了
out of concern it might be dangerous to transmit messages into space.
所以向太空发送信息可能是十分危险的
In reality, other radio observatories like Arecibo
实际上，其他射电天文台比如阿雷西博
were simply not available on the dates requested.
只是不能在计划的那几天使用
It had nothing to do with malevolent aliens.
这与恶意的外星人毫无关系
Zaitsev spent over a month explaining this to the agency
扎伊采夫花了超过一个月的时间向该机构解释此事
before Chafer and his team were allowed to resume broadcasting
直到六月的最后一天
on the last day of June.
查弗和他的团队才被允许继续广播
The first target was 16 Cygni A,
第一个目标是天鹅座 16 A
a sunlike star that's part of a ternary system.
这是一颗类似太阳的恒星，属于一个三合星系统
In other words, it's a system of three stars with Cygni A
换句话说，这是一个包含三颗恒星的系统，
being encircled by a small red dwarf labeled C,
其中天鹅座 A 被一颗标记为 C 的小型红矮星环绕
and together, they orbit another sunlike star labeled B
然后他们一起在六倍于旅行者一号与太阳距离的地方
that's nearly six times further away than Voyager 1 is from the Sun.
绕着另一颗被标为 B 的类太阳恒星运行
While Cygni B does have one confirmed planet,
虽然天鹅座 B 确实拥有一颗已确认的行星
it's an enormous gas giant that patrols the entire habitable zone,
但它是一颗轨道横跨整个宜居带的气态巨行星
making it impossible for an earthlike planet within that region
使得该区域内类地行星
to maintain a stable orbit.
无法维持稳定轨道
While the transmission was specifically directed at Cygni A,
虽然这次传输是专门对准天鹅座 A 星的
the situation doesn't improve much because, as far as we know,
但情况并没有好多少
it doesn't have any planets.
因为据我们所知它没有任何行星
Instead, it's orbited by Cygni C
相反，绕着它转的是天鹅座 C 星
at about twice the distance between the Sun and Pluto.
它们之间的距离约为太阳与冥王星之间距离的两倍
It's definitely possible for an earthlike planet to be sandwiched between them,
它们之间确实有可能夹着一个类地行星
but it all comes down to the precise orbit of Cygni C, which is currently unknown.
但这取决于天鹅座 C 的公转轨道，目前尚不清楚
The second target was Gliese 746, a binary system composed of a sunlike primary
第二个目标是格利泽 746，这是一个由类太阳的主星
and a smaller companion, of which very little is known.
和一颗较小伴星组成的联星系统，人们对它所知甚少
The distance between them is less than that between the Sun and Mercury,
它们之间比太阳与水星还要近
so there's no chance of finding an earthlike planet
因此在它们的周围
in a stable orbit around either one.
都不可能存在具有稳定轨道的类地行星
However, there is such a thing as circumbinary planets
然而，确实存在一种环联星运转行星
that orbit two stars at once.
能够同时围绕两颗恒星公转
With a system as tightly bound as Gliese 746,
像格利泽 746 这样紧密的系统
there's plenty of space for such a planet to exist, but so far, nothing.
仍有充足的空间让这类行星存在，但迄今为止，并没有
The third target was 15 Sagittae.
第三个目标是天箭座 15
It could be described as a binary system because Sagittae A
它也可以看作是一个联星系统，因为天箭座 A
is orbited by this tiny companion labeled B.
被一颗小小的伴星 B 环绕
But Sagittae B is what's known as a brown dwarf
但天箭座 B 是一颗褐矮星，
that falls somewhere between a planet and a star.
介于行星与恒星之间
It's dozens of times more massive than all the planets in the Solar System combined,
它的质量是太阳系所有行星总和的数十倍
but still not quite massive enough to shine like a star.
却仍不足以像恒星那样发光
Apart from Sagittae B, no other bodies have been detected,
除了天箭座 B 之外，这一系统里没有发现其他天体
and the system is a bit on the younger side
其年龄属于年轻的那一类
at approximately two and a half billion years old.
大约有二十五亿岁
Finally, the fourth target was Gliese 777 A,
最后，第四个目标是格利泽 777 A
a sunlike star that is once again encircled by a red dwarf companion.
这还是一颗类太阳恒星，被一颗红矮星伴星所环绕
Except, this time, the two are separated by such an enormous distance
只不过这一次，两者相距极其遥远
that it takes them upwards of 100 000 years to complete an orbit.
以至于它们绕行一周需要超过十万年
Nevertheless, the target was 777 A, and it's home to three confirmed planets.
无论如何，目标是 777 A，它拥有三颗已确认的行星
Two of them are many times more massive than Earth
其中两颗的质量都是地球的数倍
and are practically hugging the star,
且几乎紧贴着恒星运行
while the third is a bit more massive than Jupiter and is much further away.
而第三颗的质量略大于木星并且距离恒星远得多
In between them lies the habitable zone,
它们之间存在着宜居带
which does appear to be stable enough to host an earthlike planet,
该区域似乎足够稳定，可以容纳一颗类地行星
but none have been detected to date.
但到目前为止也没有发现一个
While all of these stars are within the general solar neighborhood,
尽管这些恒星都位于太阳系的邻近区域
we still have to wait until the 22nd century
但根据相对论，我们仍需等到二十二世纪
until any response could relativistically be received.
才有可能接收到回复
A fact that might come as a disappointment to some of you,
这一事实可能会让你们中的一些人感到失望
but no doubt a relief to others.
但无疑也会让另一些人感到宽慰
But it wasn't just the general public.
并不仅仅是普通民众如此
A growing number of experts had begun to question the ethics and wisdom
越来越多的专家开始质疑主动与外星文明沟通的
of deliberate communication attempts.
伦理性和明智性
Among them was Carl Sagan, who, as early as 1983,
其中就包括卡尔·萨根，
began arguing in favor of "listening rather than sending."
他早在 1983 年就开始主张“倾听而非发送”。
Not so much because he feared invasion,
这并非因为他担心外星入侵
but because he felt that contacting aliens was premature.
而是因为他认为联系外星文明为时过早
He wrote that
他写道：
"it is not yet clear that we have anything particularly interesting to say"
“目前尚不清楚我们有什么特别有趣的内容值得分享
due to what he described as our "backward status."
因为我们仍然处于‘落后状态’”
In other words, a baby civilization like humanity
换句话说，像人类这样的初级文明
probably won't have much to offer one that's been around
可能无法为已存在数百万甚至数十亿年的文明
for millions or billions of years,
提供什么信息
so we should prioritize intelligence gathering
因此我们应该优先收集情报
before we start shouting at the sky.
而不是贸然向宇宙高声呼喊
But astronomers like Alexander Zaitsev strongly disagreed with that position,
但像亚历山大·扎伊采夫这样的天文学家强烈反对这一观点
essentially arguing that we must not give into fear of the unknown.
认为我们绝不能屈服于对未知的恐惧
Sure enough, just a few months after the first Cosmic Call,
果然，在第一次宇宙呼叫发出仅几个月后
Zaitsev and others began work on yet another message.
扎伊采夫等人便开始着手准备另一条信息
In early 2000, a youth community center in Moscow
2000 年初，莫斯科一家青少年社区中心
was preparing to host a festival to celebrate the new millennium.
正筹备举办一场庆祝千禧年的节日活动
During the preparations, an astronomy teacher named Boris Pschenichner
筹备期间，一位名叫鲍里斯·普舍尼希纳的天文老师
suggested to some of his students that they should create an interstellar message
建议学生创作一条星际信息
to be presented during a space-themed portion of the event.
以在活动的太空主题环节中展示
The project was spearheaded by two teenagers
该项目由两名青少年牵头
named Egor Kiselev and Vladimir Filippov
分别是伊戈尔·基谢列夫和弗拉基米尔·菲利波夫
who quickly devised a message composed of both music and pictures.
他们迅速设计出了一条包含音乐和图像的信息
Once the project had been approved by a committee that included Alexander Zaitsev,
项目在获得包括亚历山大·扎伊采夫在内的委员会批准后
it was decided to transmit the message sometime the following year
决定于次年某个时间发送这条信息
to commemorate the 40th anniversary of the first crewed spaceflight
以纪念 1961 年由宇航员尤里·加加林
by cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin in 1961.
完成的首次载人航天行动四十周年
Zaitsev expanded upon the ideas of Kiselev and Filippov
扎伊采夫在基谢列夫和菲利波夫想法的基础上进一步拓展
by suggesting the message be divided into three distinct signal types:
提出将信息分为三种不同的信号类型
constant,
分别是恒定信号
continuous,
连续信号
and discrete.
以及离散信号
The constant signal would be sent first
恒定信号会先发送
to let the aliens know that they've picked up something strange.
来让外星人知道他们接收到了某种异常信号
That probing beacon would then transition into a continuous signal
随后这一探测信标将转为连续信号
conveying the musical component of the message.
传递信息中的音乐部分
Finally, two discrete frequencies would be used to broadcast binary-coded images.
最后用两个离散频率来传输二进制编码的图像
According to Zaitsev, the three formats
据扎伊采夫所说，这三种格式
represented the language of nature, emotion, and logic.
分别代表了自然、情感和逻辑的语言
A total of nine musical compositions were selected,
共选定了九首音乐作品
and Zaitsev proposed using an electronic instrument known as a theremin.
扎伊采夫提议使用一种名为特雷门琴的电子乐器
Partly because it generates a smooth monophonic signal with minimal overtones,
部分原因在于它能产生平滑的单音信号且泛音极少
but also because the theremin was a Russian invention.
同时也因为特雷门琴是俄罗斯的发明
The visual portion of the message was composed of 28 bitmaps
该信息的视觉部分由 28 张位图组成
primarily designed by Kiselev and Filippov.
主要由基谢列夫和菲利波夫设计
The first image depicts a wave within a circle,
第一幅图像描绘了一个圆圈内的一道波
which is meant to convey to the aliens that the circle's diameter
旨在向外星人传达该圆的直径
is equal to the wavelength of the transmission.
等于此次传输信号的波长
If they correctly make that guess,
他们猜出这一点后
the next image is meant to be scaled so that this circle
就可以将下一幅图像按比例缩放
with a human face in the center
使得这个中央带有人脸的圆圈
matches the diameter of the circle from the previous image.
与上一张图里的圆的直径相等
Doing so would enable them to decode other components,
这样做将使他们能够解码其他部分
like how this wavelength corresponds to a spectral absorption line of water.
比如这个波长是如何对应于水的光谱吸收线的
Without going into too much detail here,
此处无需过多细节
it's meant to highlight the significance of water to life here on Earth.
这是为了强调水对地球上生命的重要性
While some of the illustrations tried to convey information using science and logic,
虽然部分插图试图通过科学和逻辑传递信息
a lot of it was artistically motivated.
但其中许多内容都源于艺术创作
Life inhabits the ocean, land, and atmosphere,
生命栖息于海洋、陆地和大气中
represented by dolphins, humans, and birds
分别以海豚、人类和鸟类来表示
that the aliens will, of course, have no chance of deciphering.
外星人当然毫无可能解读这些符号
The ten circles along the edge, numbered 1 through 10,
边缘上的十个圆圈，编号一到十
not only symbolize our use of a base-ten numeral system,
不仅象征我们使用十进制数字系统
but also correspond to the next ten images.
还对应接下来的十幅图像
The first of which is this side-view of our galaxy
第一张是这张银河系的侧视图
with an arrow pointing at us.
图中有一个箭头指向我们
The second is a schematic of the Solar System.
第二张是太阳系的示意图
The third gets a bit closer.
第三张则更近了一些
The fourth gets closer still.
第四张更近了
Then there's a family,
接着是一个家庭
a house,
一栋房子
and a close-up of a person.
和一个人的特写
Towards the end, there's also a yin and yang symbol,
接近结尾处还有一个阴阳符号
two games of tic-tac-toe,
两个井字棋图案
and an illustration of the telescope used to transmit the message.
以及用于发送这条信息的望远镜的示意图
But it doesn't end there because the next image is the same emblem we saw before,
但这还没完，因为下一张图像正是我们之前见过的那个徽标
except the ten outlying circles
只不过外围的十个圆圈
have now been filled in with the ten preceding images.
被前面的十张图像填满
Exactly why they're laid out in this circular pattern in this particular order,
它们为何以这种顺序，用这种环形图案排列
or even what function it all serves,
甚至这一切究竟有何作用
I couldn't tell you.
我都无法告诉你
But, again, the emblem was intended to be both informational and artistic.
但需要强调，这个徽章兼具信息性和艺术性
Following the emblem sequence, the next three images
在标志序列之后，接下来的三幅图像
contain some text written in both Russian and English.
包含了一些用俄语和英语书写的文本
Approximately 1 000 students between the ages of 13 and 18 participated in the project,
大约一千名年龄在十三至十八岁之间的学生参与了这一部分
and this is an extreme abbreviation of their many proposed greetings.
这是对他们提出的众多问候语的极度简缩版本
It very innocently ends with...
它非常天真可爱地以这句话结尾
Signed by...
并且署名为...
The final twelve bitmaps depict illustrations that we've already seen,
最后十二幅位图展示了我们已经见过的图
each one captioned with a brief description in both Russian and English.
每幅图都配有俄语和英语的简短说明
They're meant to function as a sort of dictionary
它们旨在充当一种词典
with the hopelessly optimistic goal
怀着一种不太实际的希望
of teaching the aliens how to read the aforementioned greeting.
试图教会外星人如何解读前述问候语
The three components of the message, starting with the probing signal,
这条信息包含三个部分：首先是探测信号
followed by the music, and the 28 bitmaps,
然后是音乐，最后是 28 幅位图
were then transmitted from the Evpatoria Deep Space Center on August 29, 2001.
它们于 2001 年 8 月 29 日从叶夫帕托里亚深空通信中心发出
Much like the first Cosmic Call,
与第一次宇宙呼叫类似
the Teenage Message was transmitted multiple times over multiple days.
青少年信息在几天内多次发送
This time to six different targets.
这一次则发送给了六个不同的目标
The first one was Gliese 797 A, an as of yet planetless but sunlike star
第一个目标是格利泽 797 A，这是一颗目前尚未发现行星、但类似太阳的恒星
that forms a wide ternary system with two smaller companions.
它与两颗较小的伴星共同构成了一个宽距三合星系统
The second target was 37 Geminorum,
第二个目标是双子座 37
a solitary sunlike star that has yet to show any signs
这是一颗孤独的类太阳恒星
of hosting a planetary system.
至今尚未显示出拥有行星系统的任何迹象
Target number three was another sunlike star known as 47 Ursae Majoris,
第三个目标是另一颗类太阳恒星，名为天牢三
which is home to three confirmed planets.
已确认拥有三颗行星
They all appear to be gas giants, and the one closest to the star
它们似乎都是气态巨行星，其中最靠近恒星的那颗
is grazing the outer edge of the habitable zone.
正擦过宜居带的外缘
Because it's more than twice the mass of Jupiter,
由于它的质量超过木星的两倍
its immense gravity renders nearly the whole outer half of the habitable zone
其巨大的引力使得宜居带外侧近一半的区域
completely off limits.
完全无法供行星稳定存在
An earthlike planet within this region
位于这一区域的类地行星
simply wouldn't be able to maintain a stable orbit.
根本无法维持稳定的轨道
But if such a planet were to be located further inwards,
但如果这样一颗行星位于更靠内的区域
things look a lot more optimistic.
情况就会乐观得多
The fourth target was Gliese 547 A.
第四个目标是格利泽 547 A
Once again, it's a sunlike star that forms a wide binary system
这又是一颗宽距联星系统中的类太阳恒星
with a small brown dwarf companion.
它有一颗小型褐矮星伴星
Apart from that, no planets as of yet.
目前没发现行星
Target number five was yet another sunlike star known as Gliese 327
第五个目标是另一颗类太阳恒星，名为格利泽 327
with no confirmed planets.
尚未确认拥有行星
It does, however, show signs of being surrounded by either one
但它确实显示出被一个或多个碎片带
or multiple belts of debris.
环绕的迹象
But the precise mass, composition, and extent of this debris remains to be seen.
但这些碎片的确切质量、成分和范围仍有待观测
Finally, the sixth target was Gliese 788.
最后，第六个目标是格利泽 788
It is yet another solar analog with neither stellar nor planetary companions.
它又是一颗既无恒星伴星也无行星伴星的类太阳恒星
All but one of the targets are more than 50 lightyears away, so
所有目标中只有一个距离我们不到五十光年
the minimum response time is over a century.
因此最短的回复时间也超过一个世纪
The one exception is 47 Ursae Majoris at 45 lightyears,
唯一的例外是距离四十五光年的天牢三
so we could hear back from the Majorans as early as 2092.
我们最早可能在 2092 年收到来自天牢三人的回复
As the name Encounter 2001 would seem to imply,
正如“相遇 2001”这个名字所暗示的那样
the Millennial Voyage was scheduled to launch by the end of 2001.
千禧航行计划于 2001 年底前发射
But shortly before the start of that year,
但在那年发射前不久
the project was quietly rebranded as Team Encounter.
该项目被悄然更名为 Team Encounter
While it's difficult to know exactly what was going on behind the scenes,
虽然很难确切了解幕后究竟发生了什么
it seems like they vastly overestimated the public's interest
但他们似乎严重高估了公众
in sending messages into space.
对向太空发送信息的兴趣
As mentioned before, the team expected to attract
如前所述，该团队预计能吸引
somewhere between 1.5 and 4.5 million customers.
一百五十万到四百五十万个客户
A few months after launch, they had sold 45...
但在发射的几个月后，他们卖出了 45...
...tickets.
...张票
While sales ramped up quite a bit before the first Cosmic Call,
尽管在首次宇宙呼叫前销量大幅上升，
43 000 customers was still a far cry from the millions they had anticipated.
四万三千名客户仍远低于他们预期的数百万
With such lackluster performance,
业绩如此惨淡
the company had no choice but to push back the launch date
公司别无选择，只能将千禧航行的发射日期
of the Millennial Voyage by several years and changed the name to Team Encounter.
推迟数年，并更名为 Team Encounter
But even after significant delays, a few celebrity endorsements,
但即便多次大幅推迟，请名人来代言
and numerous attempts to get people interested,
以及屡次尝试激发公众兴趣
sales lagged behind expectations by a wide margin.
销售业绩仍远远低于预期
By the summer of 2003, the company's main investor finally pulled the plug,
到 2003 年夏天，公司的主要投资者终于撤资
and the project was summarily abandoned.
该项目随即被仓促放弃
While this meant the Millennial Voyage was dead,
虽然这意味着千年航行计划就此终结
Team Encounter did at the very least uphold their promise
但 Team Encounter 至少兑现了他们的承诺
of transmitting a second Cosmic Call.
成功发送了第二次宇宙呼叫
The composition of which was very similar to the first.
其内容与第一次非常相似
Just like before, it started with a primer
和之前一样，它始于一个引导
designed by Yvan Dutil and Stphane Dumas.
由杜提尔和杜马斯设计
However, they actually created a new set of glyphs,
他们实际上创造了一套新的字形
even more noise-resistant than the first.
比第一套更具抗噪能力
The 23 bitmaps were also redesigned and combined into one large image,
这 23 幅位图也被重新设计并合并成一幅大图
but the contents of the primer stayed more or less the same.
但引导的内容基本保持不变
This was followed by a copy of the Arecibo Message,
后面附上了阿雷西博信息的副本
a few images from the Teenage Message,
几幅来自青少年信息的图像
a description of the now canceled Millennial Voyage,
对现已取消的千禧航行计划的描述
and greetings by the staff at Team Encounter.
以及 Team Encounter 工作人员的问候
Last but not least was the commercial payload.
最后是重要的商业内容
This included not just the names and greetings of more than 100 000 customers,
其中不仅包括了超过十万名客户的姓名和问候语
but also more unique contributions like a chatbot program called Ella,
还包括一些更为独特的内容，例如一个名为 Ella 的聊天机器人程序
the contents of an entire website,
一个完整的网站内容
and the song Starman by David Bowie.
以及大卫·鲍伊的歌曲《Starman》
All of which was, of course, converted into binary
当然，所有这些内容都被转换成了二进制
before being transmitted into space
并于 2003 年 7 月 6 日
from the Evpatoria Deep Space Center on July 6, 2003.
从叶夫帕托里亚深空通信中心发射向太空
[Hugh Downs] The people of the planet Earth
地球的人类
send their greetings and friendship to you, across lightyears of interstellar space.
跨越数光年的星际空间，向你们致以问候与好意
The message we send to you today contains information about our Solar System,
我们今天发送给你们的信息包含了有关我们的太阳系
our planet, and ourselves.
我们的星球以及我们自身的内容
We invite you to contact us and to share your knowledge, culture, and wisdom.
我们邀请你们与我们联系，并分享你们的知识、文化与智慧
May this Cosmic Call open an exciting dialogue between our two stars
愿这次宇宙呼叫开启我们银河系中双方星辰间的
here in the Milky Way galaxy.
精彩交流
Much like the first Cosmic Call, the second was beamed toward multiple targets.
与第一次宇宙呼叫类似，第二次也向多个目标发射了信号
There were five in total, and the first one was Gliese 67.
共有五个目标，第一个是格利泽 67
It's a binary system composed of a sunlike primary
这是一个联星系统，由一颗类太阳的主星和一颗红矮星伴星组成
and a red dwarf companion that takes about 20 years to complete an orbit.
后者大约需要二十年才能完成一次公转
While neither one is known to harbor any planets,
尽管目前尚不清楚其中任何一颗恒星是否拥有行星
and the distance between them is less than that
且它们之间的距离在最近时
between the Sun and Jupiter at closest approach,
不到太阳与木星之间的距离
they're still far enough apart for an earthlike planet
但它们仍然相距够远，使得各自宜居带内的类地行星
within their respective habitable zones to maintain a stable orbit.
能够维持稳定的轨道
The second target was Gliese 208 A,
第二个目标是格利泽 208 A
which is only about half the size and mass of the Sun
它的大小和质量仅为太阳的一半左右
and forms a wide binary system with an even smaller companion.
并与一颗更小的伴星组成一个宽距联星系统
No planets as of yet, and it could be as young as half a billion years,
目前尚未发现行星，而且它的年龄可能仅有五亿年左右
which would make it unlikely to host a spacefaring civilization.
这样的年龄意味着它不太可能孕育出具备星际航行能力的文明
Target number three was 55 Cancri A,
第三个目标是轩辕增十九
a star that's a bit fainter and colder than the Sun,
这是一颗比太阳稍暗、稍冷的恒星
with a distant red dwarf companion.
它拥有一颗相距遥远的红矮星伴星
It's the host of five confirmed planets,
它拥有五颗已确认的行星
with the fourth one, dubbed Harriot, orbiting within the habitable zone.
其中第四颗名为哈里奥特的行星，运行在宜居带内
Now, because Harriot's mass is at least three times that of Neptune,
由于哈里奥特的质量至少是海王星的三倍
it's not a very likely candidate for life as we know it.
它不太可能孕育我们所熟知的生命
But it's not inconceivable for life to have emerged on an earthlike moon
但生命也有可能出现在围绕哈里奥特运行的
in orbit around Harriot.
类地卫星上
Not only that, but it is possible for an earthlike planet to maintain a stable orbit
不仅如此，这颗类地行星
within the outer half of the habitable zone,
有可能在外侧宜居带的一半区域内维持稳定轨道
although simulations suggest that such a planet is far more likely to have formed
尽管模拟表明这样的行星
just outside of it.
更可能形成于该区域之外
The fourth target was 47 Ursae Majoris,
第四个目标是天牢三
which was previously the target of the Teenage Message,
它此前曾是青年信息的目标
making this the first time we've signaled the same star more than once.
这使得我们首次对同一颗恒星发送了不止一次信号
Finally, the fifth target was Gliese 49,
最后，第五个目标是格利泽 49
which has a lot in common with the second target.
它与第二个目标有许多共同之处
It's a red dwarf about half the size and mass of the Sun
它是一颗红矮星，大小和质量约为太阳的一半
that probably forms an extremely wide binary system
很可能与一颗更小的伴星组成一个极宽的联星系统
with an even smaller companion.
其伴星比它还要小
While a planet with a mass of more than five times that of Earth
虽然已在主星周围发现了一颗质量超过地球五倍的行星
has been detected around the primary,
但由于其距离恒星过近
it's unlikely to be habitable due to its proximity to the star.
这颗行星很可能并不宜居
But even if that wasn't the case, the system is probably too young
即使宜居，这个系统的年龄也可能根本足以孕育
to host a communicative civilization in the first place.
具有对外交流能力的文明
Nevertheless, Gliese 49 is the least distant of the five targets
格利泽 49 是五个目标中距离最近的
at 32 lightyears,
有三十二光年远
meaning any potential replies could reach us no sooner than 2067.
这意味着任何回复最早到 2067 年能到达地球
Now, two years after the second Cosmic Call
如今，在第二次宇宙呼叫发出两年后
in the small European Republic of San Marino,
在欧洲小国圣马力诺共和国
Hungarian astronomer Ivn Almr proposed a ten-point scale
匈牙利天文学家伊凡·艾尔玛提出了一种十分制量表
for quantifying the risk of interstellar messages.
为衡量星际信息的风险提供了量化标准
According to this scale, a transmission like the Arecibo Message
根据这一量表，像阿雷西博信息这样的传输
carries a risk of 8, which is characterized as a far-reaching threat to humanity.
风险值为八，定性为对人类具有深远影响的威胁
Meanwhile, the two Cosmic Calls and the Teenage Message
与此同时，两次宇宙呼叫和青年信息
supposedly carry a risk of 7, giving them a threat level of high.
据称风险值为 7，使其具有高威胁等级
While the risk factor is partially determined by objective metrics
风险因素部分由信号强度和持续时间等
like signal strength and duration,
客观指标决定
it's also based on the contents of a message.
但也取决于信息的内容
This makes the San Marino Scale inherently subjective,
这使得圣马力诺量表本质上具有主观性
and it also fails to consider other crucial factors like the distance to
并且它也未能考虑其他关键因素
and habitability of the target.
例如目标的距离及其宜居性
That being said, the creation of the San Marino Scale
话虽如此，圣马力诺指数的创立
is a fascinating development because
仍是一个引人深思的进展
it highlights just how contentious the transmission debate had become.
它凸显了关于主动发送信号的争论已变得多么激烈
Many prominent figures within the SETI community,
SETI 社区中的许多知名人士
that being the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence,
即“搜寻地外文明计划”的成员
had become a lot more hesitant or outright opposed
变得愈发犹豫甚至公开反对
to what had come to be known as METI,
后来被称为 METI 的做法
Messaging Extraterrestrial Intelligence.
即“主动向地外文明发送信息”
A term coined by none other than Alexander Zaitsev
这一术语正是由亚历山大·扎伊采夫
during the creation of the Teenage Message.
在创建青年信息时提出的
Pushing back against this growing opposition to METI,
面对日益增长的对 METI 的反对声音
Zaitsev reasoned that
扎伊采夫反驳道：
"in a galaxy where everyone is listening and no one is speaking...
“在一个所有人都在倾听却无人发声的银河系中...
...someone has to make the first move."
...总得有人迈出第一步”
He called attention to a poll showing that 78% of more than 140 000 SETI enthusiasts
他提请人们注意一项调查显示，超过十四万名 SETI 热衷人士中，实际上有 78%
were, in fact, in support of METI.
是支持 METI 的
What he doesn't mention is that over half of those same respondents
他没有提到的是，超过半数的这些受访者
were still unsure if the aliens they were hoping to contact
仍不确定他们所希望联系的外星人
were more likely to be friendly or hostile.
更可能是友善的，还是敌对的
Throughout the 1990s,
整个 20 世纪 90 年代
there was increasing demand within NASA to launch a mission to Pluto.
NASA 内部对发射冥王星探测任务的呼声日益高涨
At the time, it was the last unexplored planet of the Solar System,
当时，冥王星还是太阳系中最后一颗未被探索的行星
and even our most powerful telescopes could resolve nothing but a nebulous disc.
即使我们最强大的望远镜也只能分辨出一个模糊的圆盘
After numerous failed attempts to secure the necessary funding,
在多次争取必要资金未果之后
the spacecraft New Horizons was successfully launched on January 19, 2006.
新视野号探测器于 2006 年 1 月 19 日成功发射
[Announcer] Five.
五
[Announcer] Four.
四
[Announcer] Three.
三
[Announcer] Two
二
[Announcer] One.
一
We have ignition and liftoff of NASA's New Horizons spacecraft
我们已点火，NASA 的新视野号航天器成功升空
on a decade long voyage to visit the planet Pluto and then beyond.
踏上这趟长达十年的远征，目标是飞掠冥王星并探索更遥远的宇宙深处
After borrowing some extra speed from the almighty Jupiter,
从强大的木星借得额外速度后
New Horizons finally caught up with Pluto in 2015.
新视野号终于在 2015 年追上了冥王星
At the time of the launch, Pluto was still recognized as a planet.
发射当年，冥王星仍被认定为一颗行星
But only seven months into the mission,
但任务开始仅七个月后
it was reclassified by the International Astronomical Union
国际天文学联合会就将冥王星重新分类
as a dwarf planet.
划为矮行星
A decision that remains somewhat controversial to this day.
这一决定至今仍颇具争议
Although, strictly semantically speaking,
尽管从严格的语义上来说
a dwarf planet is still a planet.
矮行星仍然是一颗行星
It's right there in the name.
名字里就已经写得很清楚了
Anyway, much like the Pioneer and Voyager probes,
无论如何，与先驱者号和旅行者号探测器非常相似
New Horizons continued on into deep space, destined to leave the Solar System
新视野号将继续飞向深空，最后离开太阳系
and roam the galaxy.
并在银河系中漫游
Yet unlike its predecessors,
然而与它的前辈不同的是
it does not carry a message.
它并未携带任何信息
According to lead scientist Alan Stern,
据首席科学家艾伦·斯特恩称
the inclusion of a plaque was brought up during the planning stages.
在策划阶段曾有过将一块牌匾带上的提议
But he ultimately rejected that proposal
但他最终予以否决
out of concern it might spark some sort of controversy
因为担心该提议可能引发某种争议
that could take focus away from the mission.
从而分散注意力影响任务的核心目标
Not unlike what happened back in the '70s, when
这与上世纪七十年代的情形并无二致
actual adult human beings realized that underneath our clothes
那个时候真正的成年人意识到
is not more clothes.
我们衣服下面正是赤裸裸的肌肤
Given that New Horizons was but the latest
鉴于新视野号
in a long series of failed attempts to launch a mission to Pluto,
只是此前一系列飞往冥王星任务失败后的最新尝试
Stern did not want to risk yet another delay or worse.
斯特恩不想再冒延误的风险，更不用说一些更糟糕的情况
But as stern as Stern might have been regarding a deliberate message,
但尽管斯特恩对刻意携带信息持坚决反对态度
he was not opposed to the inclusion of nine symbolic items described as mementos,
他并不反对在探测器的各个角落
placed within the nooks and crannies of the spacecraft.
放置九件被称作纪念品的象征性物品
The most significant of which was this aluminum canister
其中最重要的是这个铝制容器
containing the ashes of Clyde Tombaugh,
里面装着克莱德·汤博的骨灰
the American astronomer who discovered Pluto in 1930.
他是 1930 年发现冥王星的美国天文学家
Shortly before his passing in 1997,
在他 1997 年去世前不久
Tombaugh requested that his cremains be launched into space,
汤博请求将自己的骨灰送入太空
and what better way to honor that request
还有什么比让他飞越自己发现的行星更好的方式
than to sail him past the planet that he discovered.
来实现这一遗愿呢
The other eight mementos included two flags of the United States;
另外八件纪念品包括两面美国国旗
two state quarters, one from Maryland and one from Florida,
两枚州纪念币，一枚来自马里兰州，一枚来自佛罗里达州
honoring the states in which the probe was built and launched;
以纪念探测器建造和发射所在的州
a chunk of SpaceShipOne,
一块太空船一号的碎片
paying tribute to the first successful crewed spaceflight by a private company;
致敬首家成功实现载人航天飞行的私营公司
a postage stamp describing Pluto as the only planet "NOT YET EXPLORED";
一枚邮票，上面将冥王星描述为唯一一颗“尚未被探索”的行星
an off-the-shelf CD on the port side,
探测器左舷安装了一张市售光盘
loaded with the names of more than 400 000 people
其中存有超过四十万名
who signed up during an online campaign;
网络活动参与者的姓名
and another CD on the starboard side,
另一张光盘被安在右舷
loaded with notes and photographs
里面存有一些留言和照片
of people responsible for designing, building, and launching New Horizons.
它们来自于参与设计、建造和发射新视野号的人员
According to Stern, these artifacts were
据斯特恩所说，这些纪念品是
"more efforts of the heart than the head"
“更多出于情感而非理性的产物”
and were intended for us here on Earth,
它们的目标受众是我们这些地球上的普通人
not whomever might stumble upon the probe in the distant future.
而非遥远未来可能偶然发现探测器的未知存在
In fact, commercial CDs degrade over time
事实上，商用光盘会随着时间推移而老化
and become unreadable within decades or a few centuries at most.
最多在几十年到几个世纪内就会变得无法读取
Although, those estimates assume an earthlike environment,
不过这些假设是基于类似于地球的环境
not a spacecraft floating through the vacuum of space
而非一艘在太空真空中漂浮的航天器
while being shielded from a lot of otherwise damaging ultraviolet radiation
后者还通过隔热毯屏蔽了大量原本具有破坏性的
by a thermal blanket.
紫外线辐射
Somehow, longevity estimates for a CD being stored in those conditions
不知为何，在那些条件下存储的 CD 寿命估算
never came up in the search results.
不太能搜到
Anyway, the lack of a deliberate physical message
无论如何，缺少一份精心设计的物理信息让一些人感到不安
bothered some people enough that in 2013,
以至于在 2013 年
one of the makers of the Golden Records, Jon Lomberg,
黄金唱片的创作者之一乔恩·隆伯格
launched a campaign to create a digital one.
发起了一项创建数字信息的活动
The idea was for people around the world to submit
想法是让世界各地的人们提交
sounds, images, and other material
声音、图像和其他素材
that could be uploaded to one of the memory banks aboard the spacecraft.
这些内容可以上传到航天器上的一个存储器中
While there was a lot of public support for the project
尽管该项目获得了大量公众支持
and Alan Stern was open to the idea,
且艾伦·斯特恩对该想法持开放态度
the One Earth message never materialized.
但“一个地球”信息最终未能实现
After a failed Kickstarter campaign in 2017,
2017 年众筹失败后
Lomberg stated in 2020 that NASA had initially said, "Yes",
隆伯格在 2020 年说美国宇航局最初曾表示“同意”
but later changed their minds.
但后来又变卦
Even if the project had succeeded,
即使该项目成功了
the One Earth message would've been no less symbolic than the nine mementos
《一个地球》信息也不会比那九件纪念品更具实质意义
because, just like a compact disc, computer memory degrades over time.
因为就像光盘一样，计算机存储介质会随着时间推移而老化
Even in the most optimistic of circumstances,
即使在最乐观的情况下
we're talking centuries, possibly a few millennia at best.
时间尺度也得以世纪计，至多数千年
While it is a bit disappointing that no deliberate
这确实有些令人失望
lasting message was included with New Horizons,
新视野号没有携带一段刻意设计的持久信息
let's not forget that the probe itself is a message.
但记住，探测器本身就是一个信息
One that would provide any recipients with immediate confirmation
一个能立即向任何接收者证实
that they're not alone.
他们并不孤单的信息
Although, that's presuming, of course, the probe is ever found.
当然，这还得假设探测器有朝一日真的被发现
As I'm recording this,
在我录制这段内容时
New Horizons has not been directed towards any particular star system,
新视野号尚未被定向到任何特定的恒星系统
but that could change in the future.
但这种情况在未来可能会改变
Following its encounter with Pluto in 2015
在 2015 年飞掠冥王星
and this malformed space-potato in 2019,
以及 2019 年探访这颗形状怪异的太空土豆之后
the probe is now gliding through empty space
探测器如今正滑行于空旷的宇宙空间中
while astronomers keep searching for additional flyby targets.
与此同时天文学家仍在继续搜寻可供飞掠的新目标
So far, none have been detected,
到目前为止，还没有发现合适的选择
but the probe has enough juice to keep going until at least the 2040s.
而该探测器仍有足够的电力至少持续运行到 2040 年代
So a few decades from now, shortly before it runs out of power,
因此，在几十年后，就在它即将耗尽电力之前
NASA could choose to steer the probe towards a star system
NASA 可以选择将探测器转向
in its general direction of travel.
其大致航行方向上的某个恒星系统
While such a course-corrected voyage would still take untold eons, and
尽管这样一次经过航向修正的旅程仍将消耗不知道几千万年
humanity could be long gone by the time it arrives,
而且人类可能在它抵达之前早已消逝
I think it would be quite exciting to know that one of our foremost ambassadors
但若知道我们最先进的使者
was headed for something rather than nothing.
正驶向某个目标而非一片虚无，仍令人倍感振奋
In early 2008, a man named Martin Lewis
2008 年初，一位名叫马丁·刘易斯的人
approached NASA with the idea of beaming The Beatles song Across the Universe
向 NASA 提出了一个想法，将披头士乐队的歌曲《Across the Universe》
across the universe.
向宇宙深处发送
As a Beatles historian,
作为一位披头士史学家
Lewis sought to commemorate the 40th anniversary of the song's recording,
刘易斯希望用这种方式纪念这首歌录制四十周年
and NASA seems to have agreed because the year also happened to mark
而美国国家航空航天局似乎也表示同意
the 50th anniversary of the agency's founding.
因为这一年恰好也是机构成立五十周年
Using a massive antenna at the Deep Space Communications Complex
利用位于西班牙中部、马德里以西的
located west of Madrid in the middle of Spain,
深空通信综合体的一座巨型天线
the nearly 4-minute song was beamed towards Polaris, the famous North Star,
2008 年 2 月 4 日，这首将近四分钟的歌曲
on February 4, 2008.
被发送向著名的北极星——勾陈一
Former Beatles member Paul McCartney approved of the message by saying...
前披头士乐队成员保罗·麦卡特尼对此信息表示赞同，说...
But it's highly unlikely for Polaris to be inhabited.
但北极星极不大可能有生命存在
For one thing, it's not a solitary star but a system of three.
首先，它并非一颗孤立的恒星，而是一个三星组成的系统
The primary is a supergiant that's about two and a half thousand times brighter
主星是一颗超巨星，其亮度约为太阳的两千五百倍
and nearly fifty times larger than the Sun.
体积也接近太阳的五十倍
Placed at the center of the Solar System,
如果将它置于太阳系中心
its radius would extend about halfway to Mercury.
其半径将延伸至水星轨道的一半左右
Meanwhile, its closest companion is a bit more massive than the Sun
与此同时，它最近的伴星质量略大于太阳
and takes nearly 30 years to complete an orbit.
完成一次公转需要将近 30 年
This tight-knit binary system is then encircled by a third star
这个紧密的双星系统又被第三颗恒星环绕着，
that's many tens of Pluto orbits away.
后者距离它们有数十个冥王星轨道那么远
No planets have been discovered as of yet, but
迄今为止尚未发现任何行星
even if an earthlike planet with a stable orbit
但即使在其中某颗恒星的宜居带内
could be found within one of the stars' habitable zones,
找到一颗具有稳定轨道的类地行星
Polaris probably hasn't existed long enough
北极星存在的时长
for intelligent life to have emerged.
可能也不足以让智慧生命出现
While the two companions could be as old as two billion years,
两颗伴星可能已有二十亿年历史
it seems like the primary has only been around for a few tens of millions.
但主星似乎仅存在了几千万年
As if that was not bad enough,
如果希望还不够渺茫的话
Across the Universe won't arrive until the middle of the 25th century
这首歌要到 25 世纪中叶才能抵达
because Polaris is more than 400 lightyears away.
因为北极星距离我们超过 400 光年
In the spring of 2008,
2008 年春天
the brand Doritos launched a campaign in the United Kingdom called
多力多滋品牌在英国发起了一项名为
You Make It, We Play It.
“你制作，我播放”的宣传活动
The idea was for members of the public to create a short commercial about Doritos,
这一活动旨在邀请公众创作一则关于多力多滋的短广告
and the winning entry would not only be played on national television,
获胜作品不仅会在全国电视上播出
but also beamed into space.
还将被发送到太空中
From a radar station in the middle of Svalbard in the Arctic Circle,
2008 年 6 月 12 日，一段 30 秒广告的六小时循环信号
a six-hour loop of the 30-second advert departed Earth on June 12, 2008.
从北极圈内斯瓦尔巴群岛中部的一座雷达站离开地球
The target was, once again, 47 Ursae Majoris,
目标再次指向了，天牢三
meaning we've now dispatched three separate messages to this singular star.
这意味着我们已经向这颗恒星发送了三条独立的信息
Presuming the Majorans are listening,
假设天牢三人正在听，
they'll be hearing the Teenage Message in late 2046,
他们将在 2046 年底收到青年信息
the second Cosmic Call in late 2048,
2048 年底收到第二次宇宙呼叫
and an unprompted admission that we like to hasten our mortal doom
以及在 2053 年底某时收到一条不请自来的消息
by voluntarily consuming dusty triangles of death
承认我们喜欢通过主动食用布满灰尘的死亡三角
sometime in late 2053.
来加速自己的死亡
Response time?
什么时候回复呢？
Let's hope not.
还是别回复了
In the summer of 2008,
2008 年夏天
a now-defunct social media platform named Bebo
一个现已关闭的社交媒体平台 Bebo
launched a project known as A Message From Earth.
启动了一个名为《来自地球的信息》的项目
It primarily functioned as a publicity stunt to advertise the website,
它主要是一场用于宣传网站的公关噱头
and like so many initiatives before it, crowdsourced the creation of a message
和此前众多类似计划一样，都是通过邀请用户众包
by inviting its users to submit text and images.
提交文字和图片来生成一条信息
Some untold number of submissions, and several months later,
数量不详的投稿经过数月筛选后
the 501 most upvoted entries were beamed into space
2008 年 10 月 9 日，得票最高的 501 条内容
from the Evpatoria Deep Space Center on October 9, 2008.
从叶夫帕托里亚深空通信中心向太空发射
Considering that this was open to the internet,
考虑到这是开放给整个互联网的
I strongly suspect many messages were a lot less sanitized than what we just heard.
我强烈怀疑其中很多条内容都远不如我们刚刚听到的那样干净
But since participation required you to be logged in and Bebo went offline in 2013,
但由于参与需要登录，而 Bebo 在 2013 年就已下线
very little of A Message From Earth has been preserved.
因此《来自地球的信息》的大部分内容几乎没有被保存下来
Nevertheless, the target was a red dwarf known as Gliese 581
这次的目标是一颗名为格利泽 581 的红矮星
that's a lot smaller, lighter, fainter, and colder than the Sun.
它比太阳小得多、质量更轻、亮度更暗、温度也更低
What this means is that an earthlike planet within this system
这意味着该系统中一颗类地行星
has to orbit very close to its star
必须非常靠近其恒星运行
to receive the same amount of energy as the Earth.
才能接收到与地球相当的能量
So close, in fact, that the outer edge of the habitable zone around Gliese 581
事实上，格利泽 581 宜居带的外缘
is closer than Mercury is to the Sun by a wide margin.
比水星到太阳的距离还要近得多
With planets orbiting so close, it makes them vulnerable to flaring events,
由于行星轨道如此靠近，它们很容易受到耀斑事件的影响
and it just so happens that red dwarfs have a penchant for sudden bursts of radiation.
而红矮星偏偏又特别容易突然爆发辐射
Not only can these eruptions have a sterilizing effect on nearby planets,
这些爆发会将附近的行星直接灭活
but if there's one thing that life on Earth does not appreciate,
如果问地球上的生命最无法忍受的什么
it's sudden and dramatic changes to the climate.
那就是突然剧烈变化的气候
Not that we would know anything about that, now, would we?
当然，我们现在其实并不了解，对吧？
The good news is that Gliese 581
好消息是，格利泽 581
has a better chance than most of hosting an earthlike planet
比大多数恒星更有可能拥有类地行星
because it's very old, and therefore a lot less active
因为它非常老，因此比许多年轻的同类恒星
than many of its younger siblings.
活跃度低得多
It's also quite close at less than 21 lightyears,
它距离我们也很近，不到 21 光年
meaning a reply could arrive as early as 2049.
这意味着最早在 2049 年就可能收到回复
Even more promising is that shortly before
更有希望的是
and after A Message From Earth was transmitted,
在《来自地球的信息》发送前后不久
astronomers discovered not just one, but two planets
天文学家发现了不止一颗，而是两颗行星
a few times more massive than Earth
它们的质量都是地球的几倍
orbiting within the star's habitable zone.
并且都围绕着该恒星的宜居带运行
Unfortunately, follow-up studies failed to corroborate those findings,
不幸的是，后续研究未能证实这些发现
suggesting the initially planet-looking signals were nothing more than noise.
表明最初看似是行星的信号，不过是噪声
Unless additional planets can be found in the future,
除非未来能发现更多行星
any remaining hope of life
否则任何关于生命存在的希望
falls to the three confirmed planets that lie a bit further inward.
都将寄托于那三颗已被确认、轨道稍靠内的行星
However, due to their even greater proximity to the star with
然而，由于它们离恒星更近
orbital periods of only a few days,
公转周期仅有几天
chances are they're less earthlike and more mercurylike.
它们很可能不太像地球而更像水星
To commemorate the 400th anniversary
为纪念
of astronomical contributions made by Galileo Galilei and Johannes Kepler in 1609,
伽利略·伽利莱和约翰内斯·开普勒于 1609 年作出的天文学贡献四百周年
the United Nations along with the International Astronomical Union
联合国与国际天文学联合会
declared 2009 the International Year of Astronomy.
共同宣布 2009 年为国际天文年
Unsure of how best to celebrate this milestone,
由于不确定如何最好地庆祝这一里程碑
a representative of the Australian government
澳大利亚政府的一名代表
reached out to a popular science magazine known as Cosmos.
联系了一本名为《宇宙》的知名科学杂志
The magazine's editor-in-chief, Wilson da Silva,
该杂志主编威尔逊·达·席尔瓦
suggested they transmit an interstellar message
提议在即将到来的
during an upcoming annual event known as National Science Week.
国家科学周这一年度活动中发送一条星际信息
They were soon given the green light by the government,
他们很快获得了政府的绿灯
and after consulting a bunch of astronomers, NASA, and others,
在咨询了一批天文学家、NASA 及其他相关方之后
Cosmos launched a website called Hello From Earth.
《宇宙》杂志推出了一个名为“来自地球的问候”的网站
The project was described by da Silva as "Twitter to the Stars"
该项目被达·席尔瓦形容为“面向群星的推特”
because the idea was to allow anyone to submit a brief text message
因为其初衷是让任何人都能提交一条简短文字信息
of no more than 160 characters in length.
不超过 160 个字符
When the submission period came to a close less than two weeks later,
在不到两周后提交期结束时
the website had received nearly 26 000 messages.
该网站已收到近两万六千条信息
According to da Silva, less than 1% of the comments
据达·席尔瓦称，不到 1% 的留言
contained some sort of rule-breaking content like profanity, slurs, and so on.
包含某种违规内容，比如脏话、侮辱性言辞等
They were also forced by NASA
他们还被 NASA 的要求
to remove anything deemed even remotely sexual or aggressive,
删除任何被认为哪怕稍带性暗示或攻击性的内容
like the word "breast" and the phrase "all your base are belong to us",
比如“乳房”这个词以及“你们的基地都归我们了”这句话
which is just a line from an old video game that later became a meme.
后者其实只是一句老游戏的台词，后来成了梗
As someone who's old enough to have been around back when this meme was still popular,
作为一个年纪足够大、经历过这个梗还流行的时代的人
this might be one of the most depressing things I've ever had to explain in a video.
这可能是我在视频中解释过的最令人沮丧的事情了
Painful reminders that we're all stuck on a travelator towards eternal nothingness aside,
抛开一个残酷的事实——我们所有人都站在一条通往永恒虚无的自动人行道上不谈
once all the messages had been vetted and approved,
所有信息经过审核并获得批准后
they were transmitted from a large antenna
便在 2009 年 8 月 28 日
at the Canberra Deep Space Communications Complex
从位于澳大利亚东南部的堪培拉深空通信中心
in the Australian southeast on August 28, 2009.
通过一座大型天线发射了出去
Much like A Message From Earth, Hello From Earth
与来自地球的信息类似，来自地球的问候
was also directed towards the nearby red dwarf Gliese 581.
也是朝向邻近的红矮星格利泽 581 发送的
As mentioned before, observations conducted back then
如前所述，当时进行的观测
suggested the presence of two planets within the star's habitable zone,
表明该恒星的宜居带内可能存在两颗行星
but those findings have since been refuted.
但这些发现后来被推翻
Nevertheless, Gliese 581 is now the second star to be signaled more than once
尽管如此，格利泽 581 如今已成为继天牢三之后
after 47 Ursae Majoris.
第二颗被多次发送信号的恒星
While the International Year of Astronomy
虽然国际天文年主要是为
was primarily dedicated to Galileo and Kepler,
伽利略和开普勒创立的
2009 also marked the 35th anniversary of the Arecibo Message.
但 2009 年也是阿雷西博信息发送三十五周年
Something that American artist Joe Davis decided to celebrate in his own unique way.
美国艺术家乔·戴维斯决定以自己独特的方式庆祝这一事件
One of the most vital biological mechanisms on Earth is photosynthesis,
光合作用是地球上最重要的生物机制之一
the ability of some organisms like plants and algae
即某些生物如植物和藻类
to produce life-essential oxygen using water, sunlight, and carbon dioxide.
利用水、阳光和二氧化碳生成生命必需的氧气的能力
Now, a crucial component of photosynthesis is a special molecule known as RuBisCO.
光合作用的一个关键组成部分是一种名为 RuBisCO 的特殊分子
RuBisCO is what's known as a protein, or more specifically an enzyme,
它是一种蛋白质，更具体地说，它是一种酶
that's been around for billions of years.
已经存在了数十亿年
Presuming the evolution of life here on Earth is typical rather than special,
假设地球上生命的演化是典型的而非特殊的
one possible way to communicate with an alien species
一种与外星物种沟通的可能方式
would be to send them very basic biological information.
就是向他们发送非常基础的生物信息
If their path to intelligence bears any resemblance to our own,
如果他们开智的路线与我们有任何相似之处
there's a chance they'll recognize an enzyme
他们就有可能认出像 RuBisCO 这样
as ancient and rudimentary as RuBisCO.
古老而原始的酶
This was the idea that occurred to Joe Davis in late 2009.
这是乔·戴维斯在 2009 年底想到的主意
But instead of using something more conventional like binary code,
但他没有使用二进制代码之类更常规的方式
he decided to map the RuBisCO gene sequence to four increasingly syllabic phrases
而是决定将 RuBisCO 基因序列映射为四个音节逐渐增多的短语
alluding to an ancient Greek proverb.
这些短语暗指一则古希腊谚语
These were then vocalized and turned into a 15-minute audio sample
这些内容随后被朗读出来并制作成一段十五分钟的音频样本
using the text-to-speech feature on a regular iPhone.
用的是 iPhone 上的文本转语音
Now, if you feel like you couldn't quite follow all of that, no need to worry.
现在，如果你觉得有点跟不上刚才那些内容，不必担心
There's zero chance the aliens will either.
外星人也一样跟不上
Much like Davis' previous project, the RuBisCO Stars Message was largely symbolic
与戴维斯之前的项目非常相似，RuBisCO 恒星信息的大部分是象征意义
and primarily intended to evoke a reaction from people here on Earth.
其主要目的是激发地球上人们的反应
Nevertheless, using his academic connections,
戴维斯还是利用自己的学术人脉
Davis managed to book time at the Arecibo Telescope.
成功预约到了阿雷西博望远镜的使用时间
Then, on November 7, 2009,
之后在 2009 年 11 月 7 日
just over a week before the 35th anniversary of the Arecibo Message,
也就是阿雷西博信息发送三十五周年纪念日前一周多
a frequency-shifted audio recording of a synthetic voice
一段经过频率转换的合成录音
rattling off fragmentary sentences representing the RuBisCO gene sequence
以断续的句子形式表达了代表 RuBisCO 基因序列的内容
was beamed towards three nearby stars.
被传向附近的三颗恒星
The first target was TZ Arietis, a red dwarf less than 15 lightyears away
第一个目标是白羊座 TZ，这是一颗距离不到十五光年的红矮星
with one confirmed planet approaching the mass of Saturn.
已确认拥有一颗质量接近土星的行星
It's a very active flare star so
它是一颗非常活跃的耀星，因此即使能找到类地行星
even if an earthlike planet could be found, it's unlikely to host life as we know it.
也不太可能孕育我们所知的生命
Meanwhile, the third target was Kappa Ceti,
第三个目标是的类太阳恒星鯨魚座 κ1
a sunlike star barely 30 lightyears from Earth.
距地球仅三十光年左右
While it is similar to the Sun, it's also a lot younger,
虽然它与太阳相似，但它要年轻得多
making it unlikely that sufficient time has elapsed
因此不太可能有足够的时间
for a communicative civilization to have emerged.
让一个具备通信能力的文明出现
But the second target is a lot more interesting.
但第二个目标要有趣得多
It's another red dwarf known as Teegarden's Star,
它是一颗名为蒂加登星的红矮星
and while it does exhibit occasional flaring,
尽管它偶尔会出现耀斑活动
it's a lot older and much less active than most of its kind.
但它比同类恒星年老得多，活跃程度也低得多
Furthermore, it's home to three confirmed planets
此外，它拥有三颗已确认的行星
with masses very similar to that of Earth,
质量都与地球非常接近
and two of them orbit within the habitable zone.
其中两颗位于宜居带内
To quote a recent paper,
引用一篇近期论文的说法
they are "among the most Earth-like exoplanets currently known."
它们是“目前已知最类似地球的系外行星之一”
But earthlike does not necessarily mean habitable
但像地球并不一定意味着适宜居住
because flares are but one obstacle that red dwarf planets have to overcome.
因为耀斑只是红矮星的行星需要克服的障碍之一
Another potential hazard is something known as tidal locking.
另一个潜在的危险是所谓的潮汐锁定
Without going into too much detail,
简单来说，
the simplest form of tidal locking is when the rotation of a celestial body
潮汐锁定是指天体的自转周期
becomes synchronized with its orbital period.
与其公转周期同步
The most famous example of this is the Moon.
最著名的例子就是月球
It completes precisely one rotation for every orbit around the Earth,
它绕地球公转一圈的同时恰好自转一圈
which is why we only ever see one side of the Moon.
这就是为什么我们只能看到月球的一面
The reason this happens is a bit complicated, but it's tied to proximity.
这种现象发生的原因较为复杂，但与距离密切相关
The tighter the orbit,
轨道越紧密，
the more likely it is for a celestial body to become tidally locked to its host.
天体就越有可能被其宿主恒星潮汐锁定
As you can imagine, planets orbiting red dwarfs are especially susceptible,
正如你所想的那样，围绕红矮星运行的行星容易受到影响
as they have to orbit very close to their star
它们必须非常靠近恒星
to retain liquid water on their surface.
才能在表面保留液态水
Sure enough, the three planets orbiting Teegarden's Star
围绕蒂加登星运行的三颗行星
are all believed to be tidally locked, just like the Moon.
都被认为是潮汐锁定的，就像月球一样
This is less than ideal
这种情况并不理想
because it means that one hemisphere is cooked by everlasting starlight
因为这意味着一个半球被永恒的星光炙烤
while the other is plunged into eternal night.
而另一个半球则陷入永夜
Habitability estimates for such bisected worlds
对此类半明半暗世界的宜居估计
range from extremely pessimistic to cautiously optimistic
从极度的悲观到谨慎的乐观不等
because some climate models suggest
因为一些气候模型表明
warm air from the dayside creeps into the nightside,
白昼侧的暖空气会缓慢渗入黑夜侧
which pushes cold air from the nightside into the dayside, and so on.
黑夜侧的冷空气则被推向白昼侧，以此类推
The end result of which is a planet with a surprisingly temperate climate
其最终结果是一颗气候出人意料地温和的行星
that keeps water at perfect equilibrium between freezing and evaporating.
使水在凝结与蒸发之间保持完美的平衡
But even if we accept the more optimistic models,
但即使我们接受更乐观的模型
the proximity of red dwarf planets
红矮星行星的近距离轨道
also makes them less likely to retain an atmosphere in the first place.
也使它们从一开始就更难维持大气层
That's because stars tend to shed vast quantities of material into space,
这是因为恒星往往会向太空抛射大量物质
and the closer you get, the more intense that stellar wind becomes.
距离越近，这种恒星风就越强烈
As if that was not bad enough,
如果还不够
this wind is occasionally interrupted by more explosive events
这种恒星风偶尔还会被更剧烈的事件打断，
like coronal mass ejections that can expel billions of tons of superheated plasma
比如日冕物质抛射，会喷射出数十亿吨的超高温等离子体
in a matter of minutes.
整个过程只需几分钟
Here's one being ejected from the Sun with the Earth hauntingly to scale.
这里展示了一次从太阳喷发的事件，地球与之相比惊人的小
In the case of Teegarden's Star
就蒂加登星而言
the two innermost planets are between 9 and 15 times closer
其两颗最内侧的行星与恒星的距离分别是 9 和 15 倍于
than Mercury is to the Sun.
水星到太阳距离
It only takes them 11 and 5 days, respectively, to complete an orbit.
它们分别只需 11 天和 5 天就能完成一次公转
According to one recent study, that's close enough for the stellar winds alone
根据一项近期研究，在这个距离，仅恒星风
to completely strip those planets of a lasting atmosphere.
就足以完全剥离这些行星的持久大气层
While atmospheric erosion could be mitigated by a strong magnetic field
虽然强大的磁场可能缓解大气层的侵蚀状况
like the one that surrounds the Earth,
就像地球周围的磁场那样
the magnetosphere of tidally locked planets
但潮汐锁定行星的磁层
would likely be reduced by their sluggish rotation.
可能会因其缓慢的自转而减弱
All that being said, the habitability of red dwarf planets remains open to debate.
即便如此，红矮星行星的宜居性仍有待商榷
There is so much we don't know, and
我们还有太多未知
theories, simulations, and mathematical models
而理论、模拟和数学模型
can only do so much to fill in the blanks.
在填补这些空白方面的帮助也比较有限
Red dwarfs account for approximately three quarters of all stars in the Milky Way,
红矮星约占银河系中所有恒星的四分之三
so it would be a real shame if not a single one of them can support life as we know it.
如果它们当中没有一颗能够支撑我们所知的生命，那将是一件非常遗憾的事
It's possible that some environments are conducive to life while others are not.
有些环境可能适合生命存在，而另一些则不然
The tricky part is determining where that line should be drawn.
最棘手的部分在于该如何划分界限
Presuming the planets orbiting Teegarden's Star
假设围绕蒂加登星运行的行星上
have, in fact, cradled beings of sufficient intelligence,
确实孕育了足够智慧的生命体
a reply to the RuBisCO Stars Message could be heading our way
那么对 RuBisCO 恒星信息的回复
right this very moment.
可能此刻正朝我们飞来
The signal would've reached the Teegardenese back in 2022,
这一信号在 2022 年就已抵达蒂加登星人那里
which amounts to a roundtrip ETA of 2034.
预计将在 2034 年完成这一个来回
Don't forget to mark your calendars.
别忘了在你的日历上标出来
No, genuinely this time.
这次是说真的
Late one evening on August 15, 1977,
1977 年 8 月 15 日深夜
the Big Ear Telescope in the US state of Ohio performed a routine survey of the sky.
位于美国俄亥俄州的大耳朵射电望远镜对天空进行了一次例行巡天观测
A few days later, a volunteer named Jerry Ehman
几天后，一名名叫杰里·埃曼的志愿者
sat down to review the collected data.
坐下来审阅收集到的数据
What he found was a signal so exceptionally strong
他发现了一个异常强烈的信号
that he encircled the sequence on the printout sheet
强烈到他在打印纸上的数据序列旁画了个圈
and famously wrote "Wow!" in the left-hand margin.
并在左侧空白处写下了一个著名的“哇哦！”
The Wow! Signal remains a mystery to this day.
这个哇哦！信号至今仍然是个谜
Not least of all because it was never detected again
不仅是因为它之后再也没有被探测到
despite numerous attempts to do so.
即使试了再多次
The sequence 6-E-Q-U-J-5 is not some sort of code
这个序列 6-E-Q-U-J-5 并不是某种密码
but merely the intensity of the signal over time,
而是信号强度随时间变化的表示
where numbers above 9 are represented by letters to save space.
其中大于 9 的数字用字母代替以节省空间
It makes a lot more sense if we plot it onto a graph like this.
如果我们将它绘制在这样的图表上，就会清晰得多
It begins with a value of 6,
它起始于数值 6
meaning it was six times more intense than normal background noise.
意味着其强度是正常背景噪声的六倍
The signal then jumped up to 14, followed by 26,
信号随后跃升至14，接着达到26
and a peak intensity of 30 times above background.
并达到了比背景噪声高出 30 倍的峰值强度
The signal then fell back down to 19 and then 5, before it disappeared.
信号随后回落至 19，接着降至 5，随后便消失了
Each of the six samples were recorded 12 seconds apart
六个样本每个间隔 12 秒记录一次
and this 72-second rise and fall
这 72 秒的信号增强与衰减过程
is perfectly consistent with the telescope panning over the source
与望远镜随地球自转
along with the Earth's rotation.
扫过信号源的情况完全吻合
In other words, the source of the Wow! Signal
换句话说，这哇哦！信号的来源
appears to have been more or less fixed in the night sky, much like a distant star.
似乎在夜空中是固定不动的，就像一颗遥远的恒星那样
Had it been an earthbound source it would have moved with the telescope
如果它来自地球上的某个地方，那么它会随着望远镜一起移动
while things like airplanes and satellites
而像飞机和卫星这类物体
would likely have moved too fast to remain visible for the whole 72 seconds.
则很可能移动得太快，无法在整个 72 秒内持续可见
The Wow! Signal was also tantalizingly close
哇哦！信号还很神奇地接近
to the frequency of the aforementioned hydrogen line.
前面提到的氢线的频率
This makes it even less likely to be man-made because
这使得它更不可能是人为的
it falls within a protected band of frequencies reserved for radio astronomy.
因为它落在一个专为射电天文学保留的受保护频段内
On top of that, it had a very narrow bandwidth.
此外，它的带宽非常窄
What this means is that, unlike a star, for instance,
这意味着，与恒星等天体不同
which emits radiation across a wide spectrum of frequencies,
恒星会在很宽的频率范围内辐射电磁波
the Wow! Signal was very focused.
而哇哦！信号则非常集中
It's by no means impossible for a natural source to produce such a concentrated beam,
如此集中的波束并不是绝无可能自然产生
but it is unusual.
但这种情况确实罕见
This is what makes the Wow! Signal so curious.
这正是让哇哦！信号如此引人好奇的原因
It bears all the hallmarks of a technosignature.
它具备所有技术签名的特征
Just as we have identified hydrogen,
就像我们将氢——
the most abundant element in the universe, as a means of initiating contact,
宇宙中最丰富的元素——作为发起接触的手段一样
the aliens could've done the same.
外星人也可能采取了同样的做法
Just as we tend to transmit extremely brief non-repeating messages,
就像我们倾向于发送极其简短且不重复的信息一样
the aliens could be doing the same.
外星人可能也在做同样的事情
Unfortunately, the peculiar design of the Big Ear Telescope
不幸的是，大耳朵望远镜的独特设计
makes it impossible to pinpoint the source of the signal.
使其无法精确定位信号来源
The setup was such that two large swaths of sky were scanned simultaneously,
该装置的设计是同时扫描两片广阔的天空区域
but there's no way to tell them apart when looking at the data.
但在读数据时却无法区分两片区域
Even more peculiar is that the signal was only detected once
更奇怪的是，尽管采用了这种双重扫描设计
despite this dual-scanning design.
该信号却只被探测到一次
This can only mean one of two things.
这只能意味着以下两种情况之一
Scenario one is that the source had been transmitting for some
情况一，该信号源在第一次扫描前
indeterminate amount of time ahead of the first scan,
已持续发射了一段无法确定的时间
yet ceased transmitting before it could be detected again by the second.
但在第二次扫描能够再次探测到它之前就已停止发射
Scenario two is that the source began transmitting
情况二，信号源开始发射信号的时间
during the roughly three minute window between the two scans,
恰好在两次扫描之间大约三分钟的时间窗口内
and continued to do so for who knows how long.
然后重复了不知道多久
Now, for a signal to carry information, it has to exhibit some sort of pattern.
要让信号承载信息，它必须呈现出某种模式
For instance, we tend to encode our messages by using a binary pattern
例如，我们通常通过二进制模式来编码信息
that shifts back and forth between two different frequencies
这种模式在两种不同频率之间来回切换
or levels of amplitude.
或在两种幅度电平之间交替变化
The Wow! Signal did not exhibit any such pattern.
哇哦！信号并未表现出任何此类模式
Both its frequency and amplitude
它的频率和振幅
had a constant unmodulated appearance throughout the whole thing.
在整个过程中都呈现出恒定且未经调制的特征
That being said, we can't rule out the possibility
话虽如此，我们不能排除
that a sequence of fluctuations were present
存在一系列波动的可能性
but that they fell below the threshold of what the Big Ear telescope could detect.
只是这些波动的幅度低于大耳朵望远镜所能探测的阈值
No instrument has infinite resolution
没有任何仪器具备无限的分辨率
and Big Ear had some quite significant blind spots.
而大耳朵望远镜存在一些相当显著的盲区
To quote Ehman...
引用埃曼的话来说...
On the off-chance that the Wow! Signal was a message from another civilization,
假设了哇哦！信号真是来自另一个文明的信息
the National Geographic Channel decided to transmit a reply on its 35th anniversary.
国家地理频道决定在其三十五周年纪念日发送一条回复
After collecting over 17 000 tweets and about a dozen video-recorded greetings
在收集了超过一万七千条推文以及十几段
by various celebrities and public figures,
由各界名人和公众人物录制的视频问候后
the Wow! Reply was beamed into space from the Arecibo Telescope on August 15, 2012.
哇哦！回复于 2012 年 8 月 15 日通过阿雷西博望远镜向太空发射
At least that is what the public was told.
至少公众听到的是这样的说法
But after contacting someone who worked at Arecibo when this transmission took place,
但在联系到一位当时在阿雷西博工作的人后
they told me that the stress of beaming thousands of messages into space
他们告诉我，向太空发射数千条信息所带来的压力
had caused the aging transmitter to overheat and break down.
导致老化的发射器过热并发生故障
They could not recall how many messages made it through, but
他们不记得有多少条信息成功发送
it could have been as few as just a single one.
有可能少到只有一条
Now, because the details of the project had already been publicized ahead of time,
现在由于该项目的细节早已提前公开
and no correction was ever issued,
且从未发布过任何更正
everyone assumed the Wow! Reply went off without a hitch.
所有人都以为哇哦！回复顺利发送了
But not only is it unclear how many tweets were sent,
但不仅不清楚发送了多少条推文
it's also unclear where they went because the Wow! Reply had three intended targets.
而且这些推文究竟发往何处也不明确，因为哇哦！回复原本有三个目标。
They were all sunlike stars known as HD 54351, 37 Geminorum, and 55 Cancri A.
它们都是类太阳恒星，分别名为 HD 54351、天樽增一和轩辕增十九
Very little is known about the first,
人们对第一颗恒星知之甚少
and it's quite some distance away at 140 lightyears.
它距离我们相当遥远，约有 140 光年
Meanwhile, the other two are much closer
另外两颗恒星要近得多
and have both been targeted by previous METI experiments.
并且都曾被之前的 METI 实验选为目标
The person I spoke to could not recall which one was targeted first, so
与我交谈的那个人记不清哪一个目标最先被选中
my best guess is HD 54351
我只能猜是 HD 54351
because that's the one listed first in a press release about the project.
因为这是项目新闻稿中列出的第一个目标
Now, with a name like Wow! Reply,
现在，有了“哇哦！回复”这样一个名字
you'd think the three targets were located within one of the two regions
你可能会以为这三个目标位于
from which the Wow! Signal is known to have originated.
已知的哇哦！信号来源的两个区域之一
Well, if you did think that, it might be time to recalibrate your common sense
但如果你真这么想，或许是时间来校正一下你的常识了
because all three targets are not only located outside these regions
因为这三个目标不仅位于这些区域之外
but in the complete opposite direction.
而且恰恰处于完全相反的方向
The reason for this is very simple.
原因非常简单
The location where the Wow! Signal was detected
哇哦！信号被探测到的位置
was beyond the reach of the upward-facing and stationary Arecibo Telescope.
超出了仰面朝上且固定的阿雷西博望远镜的观测范围
But if that's the case, why even call it the Wow! Reply in the first place?
但如果真是这样，那最初又为什么要称它为哇哦！回复呢？
Apart from being transmitted on its 35th anniversary,
除了它是在哇哦！信号发现三十五周年之际发送之外
none of this had anything to do with the Wow! Signal.
这件事与哇哦！信号本身毫无关联
While the signal does have the hallmarks of an alien transmission,
虽然这个信号确实具有外星传输的特征
there's still a very good chance it was caused by a natural phenomenon.
但仍有相当可能是由自然现象引起的
It's just a matter of identifying the correct one.
这只是找出正确解释的问题
For instance, one recent hypothesis
例如，近几年有一种假说
tried to blame the whole episode on a pair of passing comets,
将整个事件归咎于一对掠过的彗星
but like all previous explanations,
但和之前所有的解释一样
this one has failed to withstand further scrutiny.
这一假说也未能经受住进一步的检验
More recently, a paper published in 2024 hypothesized that a powerful flare
更近，一篇 2024 年发表的论文提出假设，
ejected by something like a magnetar
认为类似磁星这样的天体所喷发出的强大耀斑
could've been amplified by a cloud of hydrogen,
可能被一团氢云放大
which would explain the signal's frequency.
从而解释了该信号的频率特征
Whether this is the solution that will finally crack the case
这究竟是最终破解谜题的答案
or be relegated to the mounting list of dead ends,
还是会沦为不断增长的死胡同清单中的一员
only time will tell.
只有时间能揭晓答案
In the early 2010s, a film editor named Pierre Fabre
在 2010 年代初，一位名叫皮埃尔·法布尔的电影剪辑师
conceived of a project dubbed Lone Signal.
构想了一个名为“孤星信号”的项目
Much like Team Encounter and the Cosmic Calls,
和 Team Encounter 和宇宙呼叫类似
Lone Signal was an attempt to commercialize interstellar messaging.
孤星信号试图将星际信息传递商业化
The project was envisioned as a social media platform
该项目被构想为一个社交媒体平台
where anyone could submit text, images, audio, and video
任何人都可以在上面提交文字、图片、音频和视频
for direct transmission into space.
以便直接向太空发送
Another similarity between Lone Signal and the Cosmic Calls
孤星信号与宇宙呼叫之间的另一个相似之处在于
was the inclusion of a primer written in a mathematical language of sorts.
两者都包含了一种以数学语言写成的引导
Constructed by planetary scientist Michael Busch,
这种语言由行星科学家迈克尔·布施构建
every component of this language is represented by a string of eight digits
其每个组成部分都用一串八位数字表示
between 0 and 7.
这些数字的范围在 0 到 7 之间
For instance, 1 + 1 = 2 looks like this,
例如，一加一等于二看起来是这样的
and here on the right is an example of some basic algebra.
右边这里则是一些基础代数的示例
Things only become more complicated from there,
从这里开始，一切才变得复杂起来
but I'll spare you the details because, according to Busch,
但我就不赘述细节了，因为据布施所说
the technique used to encode the primer into the signal
用于将引导编码到信号中的技术太过脆弱
was far too fragile to survive the years-long trip across interstellar space.
无法在穿越星际空间长达数年的旅程中幸存下来
While the signal could still be detected,
虽然信号仍可被探测到
any patterns would become scrambled along the way,
但其中的任何模式都会在传播过程中变得混乱
making it impossible to extract and decode the primer at the destination.
导致目的地无法提取和解码该引导
In other words, alien astronomers may end up with their own Wow! Signal
换句话说，外星天文学家可能会接收到他们自己的哇哦！信号
that doesn't seem to fluctuate in any meaningful way
不具有任何有意义的波动
yet whose properties may still be difficult to ascribe to a natural source.
即便其特性仍不太像是来自于自然来源
Now, what truly sets Lone Signal apart from every other initiative mentioned so far
现在，真正让孤星计划与众不同的地方在于
is that it wasn't a one-time thing.
它并非一次性行动
Instead of transmitting the primer and public greetings all in one go,
并不是一次性发送所有的引导和公众问候
Lone Signal sought to establish a permanent beacon
孤星计划旨在建立一个永久性的信标
that would continuously transmit for years or even decades.
该信标将持续发射信号，长达数年甚至数十年
To make that happen, they couldn't just book time at an active observatory
为了实现这一目标，他们不能仅仅在某个运作的天文台预约观测时间
but had to obtain long-term exclusive control over a telescope.
而必须获得对一台望远镜的长期专属控制权
After shopping around for a bit, they eventually secured a 30-year lease
经过一番寻找后，他们最终租得三十年的一座
on a decommissioned telescope in southwestern California
位于加利福尼亚州西南部的退役望远镜
called the Jamesburg Earth Station.
叫作詹姆斯堡地球站
Then, after upgrading some of its aging equipment,
在对其部分老化的设备进行升级后
Lone Signal began transmitting on June 17, 2013.
孤星信号于 2013 年 6 月 17 日开始发送
But the team behind Lone Signal had even greater ambitions.
其背后的团队有着更加宏大的计划
Their long-term plan was to raise $100 million
他们的长期计划是筹集一亿美元
and to establish a network of telescopes to continuously signal
并建立一个望远镜网络
multiple targets all at once.
以同时持续向多个目标发送信号
They likened themselves to SpaceX and hoped to create a global platform
他们将自己比作 SpaceX，并希望创建一个全球平台
from which anyone in the world could beam any random thought
让世界上任何人都能将任意想法
directly into space all day long.
在一天的任意时刻直接发送到太空中
But in a classic case of history repeating itself,
但在历史重演的经典案例中
the team behind Lone Signal, much like Team Encounter before them,
孤星信号背后的团队
vastly overestimated the public's interest in METI.
与之前的 Team Encounter 一样，都严重高估了公众向外太空发信息的兴趣
Less than two months after launch,
项目启动不到两个月
revenue from the website barely covered 2% of their operational costs.
网站收入仅勉强覆盖其运营成本的 2%
Pierre Fabre later wrote in a comment...
皮埃尔·法布尔后来在一篇评论中写道...
...and that failure led investors to ultimately pull the plug.
...而那次失败最终导致投资者撤资。
Nevertheless, the transmission target was yet another red dwarf called Gliese 526.
先不管这些，这次传输的目标是又一颗红矮星，名为格利泽 526
It's less than 18 lightyears away and about twice as old as the Sun.
它距离不到 18 光年，年龄约为太阳的两倍
While it is a relatively quiescent star with only occasional flaring,
尽管它是一颗相对宁静的恒星，仅偶尔发生耀斑
a planetary system has yet to be detected.
但目前尚未发现其拥有行星系统
Should it be home to a spacefaring civilization,
如果那里存在一个具备太空航行能力的文明
they will have upwards of two months to notice our cosmic shouting,
他们在 2031 年将有超过两个月的时间注意到
beginning in early 2031.
我们的宇宙呼叫
Back in prehistoric times,
早在很久很久以前
not long after you pressed play on this documentary,
也就是你打开这个视频之后不久
I mentioned a series of METI experiments carried out
我曾提到过一系列
by the National Space Development Agency of Japan in the mid-to-late 1990s.
由日本宇宙开发事业团在 1990 年代中后期开展的 METI 实验
Designed by young students attending a NASDA space camp,
这五幅位图图像
these five bitmap images were transmitted from the Usuda Deep Space Center
由参加 NASDA 太空营的年轻学生设计，从臼田深空中心发射
to various locations across the galaxy.
传向银河系中的多个位置
Fast forward to 2013, and the successor to NASDA,
时间快进到 2013 年，NASDA 的继任者
the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency,
日本宇宙航空研究开发机构
decided it was time to try again.
认为是时候再发送一遍了
During a similar space camp event, and using the same telescope as before,
在一次类似的太空营活动中，用着相同的望远镜
JAXA retransmitted this image of two parents and a child on September 22, 2013.
JAXA 于 2013 年 9 月 22 日重新发送了这张两名父母与一名孩子的图像
A similar bitmap depicting a human standing next to the Sun
一幅描绘了一个人类站在太阳旁边的位图
was then transmitted the following year on August 23,
于次年 8 月 23 日被发射
although it's unclear exactly what it looked like.
尽管并不清楚它长什么样
Nevertheless, both images were directed at 55 Cancri A
这两张图都被发送至轩辕增十九
which has been targeted in the past
该恒星之前就曾被作为目标
and discussed in more detail in a previous chapter.
在前一章有更详细的讨论
But much like what happened back in the '90s, the JAXA Space Camp Messages
与 90 年代发生的情况非常相似，JAXA 太空营的信息
flew as much through the radar as they did under it.
在公众间的反响与在宇宙中的差不多
Instead, these events were largely overshadowed by new developments
这些活动在很大程度上被持续进行的传输争论的
in the ongoing transmission debate.
新形势所掩盖
Most notably, in early 2015, over two dozen scientists and SETI enthusiasts,
最引人注目的是，2015 年初，二十多位科学家和 SETI 爱好者
including a pre-disgraced Elon Musk,
包括尚未身陷丑闻的埃隆·马斯克在内
signed a petition calling for a "worldwide consensus" regarding METI.
签署了一份请愿书，呼吁就 METI 问题达成“全球共识”
They took issue with the fact that past METI experiments had been
他们对过去 METI 实验
"based upon the wishes of a few individuals"
“仅基于少数人的意愿”
rather than a "broadly representative body".
而非“广泛的代表性机构”的做法提出异议
In part because the aliens are likely to be "millions of years more advanced than us",
部分原因在于外星文明可能“比我们先进数百万年”
but also because "it is impossible to predict whether [they] will be benign or hostile."
同时也因为“无法预测（它们）究竟是善意还是敌意”
The petition concluded that the potential "consequences of contact"
该请愿书指出“接触可能带来的后果”
demanded "worldwide scientific, political and humanitarian discussion"
需要在未来的发射行动之前
in advance of any future transmissions.
“于全球范围内提前展开科学、政治和人道层面的讨论”
To which an artist in collaboration with the European Space Agency responded...
对此，一位与欧洲航天局合作的艺术家作出了回应...
In early 2016, an artist and independent researcher named Paul Quast
2016 年初，一位名叫保罗·夸斯特的艺术家兼独立研究员
created a crowdsourced art project known as A Simple Response to an Elemental Message.
发起了一项众包艺术项目，名为“对一则基本信息的简单回应”
It was similar to previous initiatives, except, this time,
它与以往的计划类似，但这次
people were asked to frame their submissions as an answer to the question,
人们需要围绕一个问题来提交自己的回答：
"How will our present environmental interactions shape the future?"
“我们当前与环境的互动将如何塑造未来？”
As the question implies, the project was about climate change
正如这个问题所暗示的那样，该项目聚焦于气候变化
and sought to capture a global portrait of humanity's thoughts and feelings
旨在捕捉人类对当今世界状况的思考与感受
about the present and future state of the world.
以及对未来的展望
As explained by Quast in a few interviews,
正如奎斯特在几次采访中所解释的那样
the project was intended more as a time capsule for future generations
这个项目更多的是为后代子孙准备的时间胶囊
than any potential aliens in outer space.
而非针对外太空中可能存在的外星人
This is also reflected by the selection of Polaris as the transmission target.
这一点也体现在把传输目标定为北极星这一点
As mentioned in a previous chapter,
正如前一章所述
it's a relatively young and currently planetless system that's
这是一个相对较年轻的恒星系统，目前没有行星
highly unlikely to host life as we know it.
而且极不可能孕育我们所知的生命
Instead, Polaris was primarily selected
相反，选择北极星主要源于
due to its historical significance as the famous North Star.
其作为著名北极星的历史意义
Nevertheless, A Simple Response to an Elemental Message
对一条基本信息的简单回应
received nearly 4 000 submissions over the course of about eight months.
在大约八个月的时间里收到了近四千份投稿
In addition to the public messages,
除了公众提交的信息外，
Quast also included a few copies of the Arecibo Message,
夸斯特还加入了数份阿雷西博信息副本
81 quotes by prominent figures,
81 条来自知名人物的语录
and 70 photographs of Earth and humanity.
以及 70 张展现地球与人类的照片
All of which was then converted into binary and finally blasted into space
所有这些内容随后都被转换为二进制格式
by the Cebreros Deep Space Ground Station in central Spain on October 10, 2016.
并于 2016 年 10 月 10 日由位于西班牙中部的塞夫雷罗斯深空地面站发射向太空
According to a subsequent review by Quast,
根据夸斯特随后的一项采访
he found that just under 20% of the responses were optimistic,
他发现收到的不到 20% 的回应持乐观态度
just over 42% expressed some form of dread or concern,
略高于 42% 的回应表达了某种形式的恐惧或担忧
while the remaining 38% were largely neutral.
其余 38% 的回应则基本持中立态度
In late 2017, a Spanish music festival known as Snar
2017 年末，一个名为 Sónar 的西班牙音乐节
began transmitting brief snippets of music into space
向太空发送简短的音乐片段
to commemorate its 25th anniversary.
以纪念其成立二十五周年
Each composition was no more than 10 seconds in length
每段作品长度不超过十秒
and were provided by 38 musicians with connections to the festival.
由 38 位有关的音乐人提供
The first 18 were transmitted over the course of three days in October 2017
前 18 段于 2017 年 10 月的三天内发出
from a telescope located in the far north of Norway.
发送地点是远在挪威北端的一座望远镜
The remaining batch of 20 was then transmitted
随后，剩下的 20 段
over the course of another three days in May 2018 using the same facility.
于 2018 年 5 月的三天内通过同一设施发送出去
What makes this initiative a bit more interesting, though,
让这一计划更有趣的是，
is the fact that all 38 compositions were preceded by a primer.
所有 38 个作品前都附带了一份引导
In fact, not just one, but several.
事实上，不止一份引导，而是好几份
The first one began with two lists of prime numbers intended to attract attention.
第一份以两列素数开头，用来引起注意
While the primes were technically expressed in binary,
虽然这些质数严格来说是用二进制表示的
it would be more accurate to say that they're expressed in unary, repeated twice.
但更准确的说法是它们以重复一次的一进制表示
So 0-0-1-1 for decimal 2,
因此十进制的 2 表示为 0-0-1-1
0-0-0-1-1-1 for decimal 3,
十进制的 3 表示为 0-0-0-1-1-1
0-0-0-0-0-1-1-1-1-1 for decimal 5, and so on.
十进制的 5 表示为 0-0-0-0-0-1-1-1-1-1，依此类推
This was followed by a simple count from 0 to 255
随后是一段从 0 到 255 的简单计数
expressed using eight-digit chunks of binary code, also known as a byte.
用八位二进制代码，也就是一个字节来表示
So it goes from eight zeroes representing 0
它从代表数字 0 的八个零开始
all the way up to eight ones representing 255,
一直递增到代表 255 的八个一
the highest value possible using 8-bit encoding.
255 正是 8 位编码所能表示的最大数值
Okay, following that introductory sequence was a second primer
在这段引入序列之后，是第二个引导
that differed between the two sessions.
这个引导在两次发射中都不一样
The one included with the first batch of music was written such that
第一批音乐附带的引导
all 256 bytes represented a unique number, word, or concept.
用 256 个字节各自代表一个数字、单词或概念
These bytes were then used to convey increasingly complex ideas,
这些字节在后面被用来传达逐渐复杂的概念
much the same way it's been done in previous initiatives,
跟之前的计划所用的方法差不多
starting with some basic math before delving into things like physics and sound.
都是从基础数学开始，再深入到物理和声音等领域
The one included with the second batch of music
随第二批音乐一同发送的引导
was nearly identical to the one created by Yvan Dutil and Stphane Dumas
与杜特尔和杜马斯为第二次宇宙呼叫创建的信息
for Cosmic Call II.
几乎完全相同
Some of the components have been shuffled around,
其中的一些部分被重新排列
and there's some updated information about the telescope,
并且包含了关于望远镜的更新后的信息
but otherwise, it's exactly the same.
除此之外，内容完全相同
Immediately following that was another bitmap
紧随其后的是另一幅位图
that tried to graphically convey the concept of a byte
内容仍然是从 0 数到 255
by counting from 0 to 255 once again.
旨在用视觉的方式表达一个字节的概念
This was then followed by an image of a sine wave
随后是一张正弦波的图像
intended to visually convey the concept of sound and music.
旨在直观地传达声音和音乐的概念
Now, the target of these transmissions was
这一次传输的目标是
an ancient red dwarf known as Luyten's Star.
一颗名为鲁坦星的古老红矮星
It's a bit more than 12 lightyears away and harbors two confirmed planets.
它距离我们 12 光年多，并拥有两颗已确认的行星
The outermost of which, Luyten b, is about three times the mass of Earth
其中最外侧的行星是鲁坦 b，其质量约为地球的三倍
and orbits within the star's habitable zone.
运行在该恒星的宜居带内
In fact, it is one of the nearest earthlike planets ever discovered,
事实上，它是迄今为止发现的距离最近的类地行星之一
and it's the sole reason that this system was targeted.
而这也是该恒星系统被选为目标的唯一原因
But as mentioned previously, the characteristic dimness of red dwarfs
但正如之前提到的，红矮星特有的暗淡
places the habitable zone very close to the star.
使得宜居带非常靠近恒星
In the case of Luyten b,
就鲁坦 b 而言
it orbits about four times closer than Mercury orbits the Sun,
它的轨道距离大约只有水星绕太阳轨道的四分之一
takes less than 19 days to complete a revolution,
完成一次公转所需的时间不到 19 天
and is all but guaranteed to be tidally locked.
并且几乎可以肯定已被潮汐锁定
On the plus side, Luyten's Star exhibits minimal flaring due to its advanced age.
好的一面是，由于鲁坦星年龄较大，其耀斑活动极少
Presuming Luyten b is inhabited by an advanced civilization,
假设鲁坦 b 上居住着一个先进文明
they'd have about 11 minutes per day for three consecutive days in early 2030
他们会在 2030 年初的连续三天的 11 分钟的时间
to pick up the first batch of music,
有机会接收到第一批音乐信号
with the second arriving a few months later.
第二批信号则会在几个月后抵达
Presuming they do so, we could hear back from the Luytenians as early as 2042.
假设他们确实接收到了，我们最早可能在 2042 年收到来自鲁坦星人的回复
Okay, we've finally reached the most recent interstellar message
好，我们终于来到了一条截止这个视频制作时
as of the making of this documentary.
最新的一条星际信息
Well, kind of.
嗯，算是吧
We'll get to that in a moment.
我们稍后会讲到这一点
Following the death of Stephen Hawking in early 2018,
2018 年初史蒂芬·霍金去世后
his ashes were interred at a famous church in London called Westminster Abbey.
他的骨灰被安葬在伦敦著名的威斯敏斯特教堂
As the memorial service came to a close,
随着纪念仪式接近尾声
an original score set against Hawking's iconic voice
一首由希腊作曲家范吉利斯创作的原创乐曲
and written by Greek composer Vangelis
配以霍金标志性的声音
was simultaneously beamed into space
于 2018 年 6 月 15 日
from the Cebreros Deep Space Ground Station on June 15, 2018.
从塞夫雷罗斯深空地面站同步发射进入太空
The target was a binary system nearly five thousand lightyears away
目标是一个距离地球近五千光年的联星系统
known as V616 Monocerotis.
名为麒麟座 V616
It's composed of a star with about one-third the mass of the Sun and...
它由一颗质量约为太阳三分之一的恒星和...
...a black hole.
...一个黑洞组成
At the time, it was the nearest black hole to the Solar System,
当时，它是距离太阳系最近的黑洞
although it has since been dethroned by at least a few other candidates.
虽然此后至少有好几个黑洞取代了它的位置
Now, paying tribute to Stephen Hawking
通过将斯蒂芬·霍金的声音发射到太空中
by beaming his voice into space may seem like an odd choice,
来向他致敬，这看起来似乎是个奇怪的选择
considering he was a very outspoken critic of METI.
尤其考虑到他生前曾是 METI 非常直言不讳的批评者
But as explained by his daughter Lucy,
但正如他女儿露西所解释的那样
the broadcast was a purely symbolic gesture
这次广播纯粹是一种象征性的举动
intended not only to celebrate his scientific contributions,
不仅是为了庆祝他在科学领域的贡献
but also to fulfill his lifelong dream of going into space.
也为了实现他毕生渴望进入太空的梦想
This is further reflected by the transmission target,
这一点也体现在传输目标的选择上
as Hawking dedicated much of his life to the study of black holes.
因为霍金毕生致力于黑洞研究
Besides, we're hardly gonna make contact with aliens
再说，我们几乎不可能
in the vicinity of a black hole, right?
在黑洞附近与外星人取得联系，对吧？
Well, so, about that...
嗯...关于这一点的话
This is a view of the Solar System
这是太阳系的一个视图
showing all five interstellar spacecraft that humanity has launched to date.
展示了人类迄今为止发射的全部五艘星际的航天器
If we zoom out a bit further,
如果我们再进一步拉远视角
we can see 23 of the nearest star systems
就能看到 23 个最近的恒星系统
targeted by at least one of the radio transmissions mentioned in this video.
它们都被本视频中提到的无线电传输所瞄准过
But to see the two most distant targets, we have to zoom out to a galactic scale.
但要看到两个最远的目标，我们必须将视野拉远到银河系尺度
Here we find V616 Monocerotis, the target of Stephen Hawking's Memorial Broadcast,
在这里，我们找到了麒麟座 V616，也就是斯蒂芬·霍金纪念广播的目标
and finally Messier 13, the target of the Arecibo Message.
以及最后的梅西耶 13，阿雷西博信息的目标
But this is by no means an exhaustive list.
但这绝不是一份详尽无遗的清单
Some radio transmissions, marked here in grey,
这里以灰色标出的一些无线电传输
did not make the cut because they failed to meet one of two criteria
它们没能被选入，因为它们未能满足我为本视频设定的
that I made up for this video.
两个标准之一
The first one is that a transmission must be deliberately directed
第一个标准是，该传输必须明确指向一个
at an extrasolar target.
太阳系外的目标
After all, the goal of METI is to contact another intelligence,
毕竟，METI 的目标是联系其他智慧文明
so projects that aimlessly blast messages into space with
因此那些漫无目的地向太空发送信息
no particular target in mind do not count.
而没有特定目标星的项目并不算数
This includes signals that could accidentally be detected,
这包括可能被意外探测到的信号
like those routinely transmitted by astronomers to
例如天文学家为与航天器通信
communicate with spacecraft or map the surface of bodies within the Solar System.
或绘制太阳系内的天体表面而常规发射的信号
To give you an example, in late 1962,
举个例子，1962 年末
a group of Soviet astronomers used this absolute beast of a telescope
一群苏联天文学家利用这台庞然大物
to bounce radar signals off the surface of Venus.
向金星表面发射了雷达信号
For a bit of fun, they decided to modulate the radar pulses
为了增添一点趣味，他们决定调制雷达脉冲
to spell out the words MIR, LENIN, and USSR using Morse Code.
用摩尔斯电码拼出“MIR”、“LENIN”和“USSR”这几个词
This is sometimes described as the first interstellar message
有的时候，这被称为首个星际信息
because a lot of that radiation went right past Venus
因为其中大量辐射直接掠过金星
and continued on into deep space.
继续向深空传播
Now, if you read about this online,
现在，如果你在网上查阅相关内容
you'll find claims that some portion of that excess radiation
会发现有说法称那部分多余的辐射
is currently heading for an obscure binary system known as HD 131336
有一部分正朝着一个名为 HD 131336 的冷门双星系统进发
that's well over a thousand lightyears away.
它们在好几千光年之外
The phrasing can often make it seem as though this was
这种措辞常常让人误以为
planned by the original scientists back in 1962,
这是 1962 年原班科学家们有意为之的计划
but that is not the case.
但事实并不是这样
The true source of this claim is a forum post from 2002
这一说法的真正来源是 2002 年的一篇论坛帖子
in which an amateur astronomer did some quick back-of-the-napkin calculations
其中一位业余天文学家做了一些粗略的估算
to suggest HD 131336 might have been near the path of the signal
提出 HD 131336 可能位于信号的传播路径附近
depending on the precise time of transmission, which is unknown.
具体取决于确切发射时间，目前无从得知
Given the imprecision of that guesstimate
鉴于这种估算的不精确性
and the fact that the intended target was Venus,
以及信号原本的目标是金星
I decided not to include it on my list.
我决定不将其列入我的清单中
The second criterion is that the strength of a transmitted signal
第二个标准是，所发射信号的强度
must be greater than 100 megawatts.
必须大于 100 兆瓦
Now, for any radio astronomers watching, here I'm not talking about output power,
现在，对于任何正在看视频的射电天文学家来说，我这里所说的并不是输出功率
but the much more crucial parameter, which is the effective radiated power
而是更为关键的参数，即有效辐射功率
that accounts for things like transmission frequency and gain of the antenna.
这里考虑了诸如发射频率和天线增益等因素
For anyone curious, you can find a spreadsheet in the references
对于感兴趣的人来说，你可以在参考文献中找到一份电子表格
with all the incredibly exciting technical details.
里面包含了所有令人无比兴奋的技术细节
Anyway, there's nothing special about 100 megawatts.
100 兆瓦并没有什么特别之处
I just needed some way to filter out some of the weaker transmissions
我只是需要某种方法来挑选出较强一些的信号
from the stronger ones, and this seemed like a nice even number to draw that line.
而这个数值看起来是个不错的整数
It's neither so high that everything is excluded
它既不会高到把所有内容都排除在外
nor so low that everything is included.
也不会低到把所有内容都包含在内
It's just a way to rein in the scope of this video.
这只是一种限制本视频内容涵盖范围的方法
While I tried to be as forgiving as possible with these two criteria,
尽管我在运用这两条标准时已尽可能宽容
you could, of course, be a lot more strict.
你当然可以严格得多
For instance, it is very common to categorize METI experiments
例如，通常可以根据大多数专家认为是认真还是轻率的程度
based on how earnest or frivolous most experts perceive them to be.
来分类 METI 实验
Take the Doritos Broadcast Project as an example.
以多力多滋广播项目为例
It is typically not regarded as a genuine attempt at METI
它通常不被视为真正意义上的 METI 尝试
because transmitting a commercial into space is obviously just a publicity stunt.
因为向太空发送一则商业广告显然只是一场宣传噱头
It's rather silly, unscientific, and utterly indecipherable.
它相当愚蠢、不科学，而且信息完全无法解码
To use the terminology favored by Alexander Zaitsev, it's "pseudo-METI".
用亚历山大·扎伊采夫偏爱的术语来说，这是“伪 METI”。
But as I've stressed multiple times throughout this video,
但正如我在本视频中多次强调的那样
what we say isn't all that important
我们说了什么其实并不那么重要
because we're probably not going to be understood anyway.
因为无论如何，我们很可能根本不会被理解
What is important is that the signal has been
重要的是，这些信号
modulated or manipulated in such a way
经过了调制或处理
that it does not resemble anything else in the universe.
使其能够与宇宙中的其他事物区分开来
As long as the recipients are unable to ascribe the signal to a natural source,
只要接收者无法将该信号归于自然来源
they will have no choice but to entertain the possibility of intelligent design.
他们就别无选择，只能考虑其出自某种智慧的可能性
Besides, the distinction between genuine and pseudo-METI
此外，真 METI 与伪 METI 之间的区分
is highly subjective and inconsistent.
具有高度主观性且不够一致
For instance, the Arecibo Message is usually upheld as a prime example of METI
例如，阿雷西博信息通常被视为 METI 的典型范例
despite Frank Drake himself describing it as a publicity stunt,
而弗兰克·德雷克本人称其为一次宣传噱头
and much of it is indecipherable.
且其中大部分内容都难以破译
Likewise, the Message to Altair is typically regarded as genuine METI
同样，发向织女星的信息通常被视为真正的 METI
even though the Doritos Broadcast Project was about five times more powerful
但多力多滋广播项目功率却约为其五倍
and lasted six times longer.
且持续时间长达其六倍
Another approach would be to sort METI experiments based on the distance to
另一种方法是根据目标的距离和宜居性
and habitability of the target.
对 METI 实验进行分类
You could, for instance, exclude the Arecibo Message because
比如，你可以排除阿雷西博信息
M13 is extremely far away and unlikely to be habitable.
因为 M13 距离极其遥远，且不太可能存在宜居环境
Same thing with Stephen Hawking's Memorial Broadcast
史蒂芬·霍金纪念广播也是一样
directed at a black hole many thousands of lightyears away.
它被发送至数千光年外的一个黑洞
But here's where things get a bit tricky because
但事情在这里变得有些棘手
how do we determine when a target is too far away?
我们如何判断一个目标是否太远了呢？
In other words, how do we know when a signal is too weak or sufficiently strong
换句话说，我们怎样才能知道一个信号对于一个我们一无所知的外星文明
to be detected by an alien civilization of which we know nothing about?
是足够强还是过于弱了呢？
The simplest approach would be to assume the recipients are no more advanced than us
最简单的方法是假设接收者并不比我们先进
and use our present level of technology and scientific understanding
并把我们当前的技术水平和科学理解
as a baseline for detectability.
作为判定可探测性的基准
In other words, if we can't detect it, neither can they.
换句话说，如果我们无法探测到，那他们也不会探测到
If that's the case, they would definitely struggle
如果真的是这样，他们肯定很难
if not be outright unable to detect
甚至根本无法检测到
some of the messages mentioned in this video.
本视频中提到的一些信息
But should we really make that assumption?
但我们真的能这样假设吗？
Well, to paraphrase Carl Sagan,
如卡尔·萨根所言
any civilization even just slightly behind us
任何比我们稍落后一点的文明
wouldn't be able to receive or transmit,
都无法接收或发送信号
whereas any civilization on par with or billions of years ahead of us
而任何与我们水平相当或领先我们数十亿年的文明
could be.
则有可能做到
Odds are they will be more advanced,
他们很可能更加先进
making range and detectability estimates based on the assumption that they're not
因而基于他们并没有更先进的假设，来估算通信距离和可探测性
feel rather pointless.
就显得相当没有意义
But it feels equally pointless to assume that they are more advanced because
但假设他们更加先进似乎同样毫无意义
then it just comes down to who writes the best science fiction.
因为那样就只取决于谁编出的科幻故事更精彩了
Does more advanced mean they have instruments that are similar to our own
“更先进”是否意味着他们拥有与我们类似的仪器
but simply larger and more sensitive?
只是更大、更灵敏呢？
Does it mean they have long since abandoned radio technology
是否意味着他们早已放弃无线电技术
in favor of something else entirely?
转而采用了完全不同的技术呢？
Does it mean they have a more sophisticated understanding of physics,
是否意味着他们对物理学的理解更为深刻
and that their technology would appear to us as nothing short of magic?
他们的科技在我们看来近乎魔法呢？
Habitability estimates suffer from a similar problem because
宜居性估算方面也面临类似的问题
we obviously don't know if what we regard as habitable
因为我们显然不知道我们所认为的宜居条件
is the same as what they regard as habitable.
是否与他们所认为的宜居条件一致
Even if we assume that intelligent life can exclusively emerge
即使我们假设智慧生命
on earthlike planets orbiting sunlike stars,
只能在围绕类太阳恒星运行的类地行星上出现
that does not mean
这也不意味
they will stay there.
他们会一直留在那里
Perhaps there comes a time in the lifespan of any civilization
或许在任何文明的生命周期中，都会出现这样一个时刻
when their energy requirements outpace that which can be provided by sunlike stars?
它们的能量需求超过了类太阳恒星所能提供的限度也说不定呢？
Perhaps life is destined to seek out more extreme environments
或许生命注定是要去寻找那些
that we would never even think of as being habitable today?
我们今天根本无法想象为宜居的极端环境的呢？
Perhaps the messages we've sent towards places most unlike our own...
或许我们向那些与地球最不像的地方发送的信息...
...are the most likely to receive a response?
...恰恰是最有可能收到回应的呢？
All this ambiguity is, of course, a big reason why many are so opposed to METI
所有这些不确定性，当然正是许多人如此反对 METI 的一大原因，
because the unknown allows us to imagine the worst.
因为未知让我们不禁设想最坏的情况
For instance, in early 2010,
例如，在 2010 年初
Stephen Hawking cautioned against deliberate communication attempts
史蒂芬·霍金曾警告不要刻意尝试与外星文明沟通
out of concern that aliens might not be too dissimilar
因为他担心外星人可能与我们过去和现在的自己
from our past and present selves.
并没有太大不同
As we've already seen throughout this video,
正如我们在本视频中已经看到的那样
this pessimistic view on humanity and first contact is very common,
这种对人性和第一次接触的悲观看法非常普遍
and for good reason.
而且有充分的理由
There are plenty of examples throughout human history
人类历史上有许多例子表明
in which a less developed society
落后的社会
suffered at the hands of a more advanced one.
会蒙受来自更先进社会的侵害
The problem with pessimism, though, is that it's one-sided.
悲观主义的问题在于它只看到了一面
It would be just as easy to leverage more positive trends and behaviours
利用片面积极的趋势和行为来支持乐观的结果
in support of an optimistic outcome.
同样轻而易举
For instance, consider this critique by philosopher Guy Kahane.
例如，可以参考哲学家盖伊·卡汗的这一批评
Considering how much we've improved in a very short span of time,
考虑到我们在极短的时间内取得了如此巨大的进步
things like child mortality, homicides, and poverty are declining
诸如儿童死亡率、凶杀案和贫困等问题正在减少
while access to clean water, electricity, and life expectancy are increasing
而清洁用水、电力供应和预期寿命却在不断提高
we only have to look at ourselves to see how intelligent life might develop
我们只需审视自身就能想象智慧生命多么有可能演化成
into something we would want to meet.
一种我们愿意接触的模样
Perhaps not humanity of today since, you know, there's still...
也许并不是今天的人类，因为你知道，毕竟还有...
...plenty of room for improvement.
...还有很大的改进空间
But if we project these positive trend lines sufficiently far into the future,
但如果我们将这些积极的趋势投射到足够远的未来
it's possible that much older civilizations will have long since outgrown
就有可能发现那些更为古老的文明或许早已改掉了
their more destructive tendencies.
他们破坏性的倾向
Just as Hawking justified his belief that aliens will be hostile by saying,
正如霍金通过说这样一句话来佐证自己“外星人是敌对”的观点
"Look at all the bad things we've done,"
“看看我们做过的所有坏事”
Frank Drake justified his belief that aliens will be friendly by saying,
弗兰克·德雷克则通过说这样一句话来证明他相信外星人会友善
"Look at our capacity for growth."
“看看我们成长的潜力”
Neither argument is more or less valid than the other because
这两种论点并无孰优孰劣之分
we're obviously capable of both.
因为我们显然同时具备这两种能力
But as the anti-METI crowd will often point out,
但如反对 METI 的人经常提到的那样
this uncertainty is the problem.
这种不确定性正是问题所在
They will often argue that the mere possibility of an existential threat
他们常会争辩说，哪怕存在一丝灭绝性威胁的可能性
outweighs any potential benefits.
也足以压倒任何潜在的好处
To reiterate a quote from much earlier in the video...
再次引用本视频早前提到的一句话...
A common counterargument among those in favor of METI is that
支持 METI 的人常提出的一个反驳观点是
it's too late to worry about hostile aliens because
担心外星人怀有敌意已经为时已晚
we've been leaking radio signals into space for the better part of a century.
因为我们近一个世纪以来一直在向太空泄漏无线电信号
Anyone within about 100 lightyears of Earth could, in theory,
距离地球约一百光年内的任何文明，在理论上
detect our presence by intercepting our television broadcasts.
都能通过截获我们的电视广播信号从而探测到我们的存在
But as opponents of METI are often quick to point out,
但METI的反对者经常迅速指出
this unintentional leakage is extremely faint and diffused.
这种无意的信号泄露极其微弱且分散
While it's impossible to say what signals are
虽然无法断言哪些信号
too faint for an alien civilization to detect,
对地外文明来说过于微弱而无法探测
a weaker signal is obviously more difficult to detect than a stronger one.
但显然，较弱的信号比更强的信号更难被探测到
But it's not just about signal strength, it's also about intent.
但这不仅关乎信号强度，也关乎意图
An archer blindly shooting arrows in random directions
盲目朝随机方向射箭的弓箭手
is a lot less likely to strike a bullseye
远不如瞄准靶心的弓箭手
than the archer aiming for the target.
有可能命中靶心
Sure, radio leakage could accidentally expose our presence,
没错，无线电泄漏可能会意外暴露我们的存在
but METI goes out of its way to maximize that outcome.
但 METI 刻意地采取行动以最大化这种结果
It's the difference between a ship lost at sea
这就像是海上迷航的船
that happens to spot the faint glow of a coastal town...
只偶然瞥见了海岸小镇微弱的灯光...
...and a lighthouse.
...与一座灯塔之间的区别
There isn't much we can do about the former
我们对前者无能为力
because it's merely a byproduct of our civilization.
因为它只是我们文明的副产品
But there's plenty we could do about the latter,
而后者我们却大有可为
like, you know, not build a lighthouse.
比如，你也知道，干脆别建灯塔
While some critics advocate for precisely that, a planetwide ban on METI,
尽管一些批评者主张的就是一点，即在全球范围内禁止METI
such proposals are often countered by what's known as the SETI Paradox.
但这类提议常常遭到所谓“SETI 悖论”的反驳。
It goes something like this.
悖论大致是这样的
If we conclude that METI is too risky,
如果我们认为 METI 风险太大
and other civilizations reach that same conclusion,
而其他文明也得出了同样的结论
what would be the point of SETI if no one is transmitting?
那么如果没人发送信号，SETI 还有什么意义呢？
To quote the man who coined the term...
用创造这个词的人的话来说...
The obvious problem with this argument is the assumption that all civilizations
这个论点的明显问题在于，它假设所有文明
independently and inevitably reach the same conclusion.
都会独立且必然地得出相同的结论
Even if we decided to cease transmitting tomorrow,
即使我们决定从明天起停止发射信号
that doesn't mean all other civilizations must behave as we do.
也不意味着所有其他文明都必须像我们一样行事
In fact, this argument doesn't work even if METI is universally rejected
事实上，即使 METI 普遍都被拒绝，这一论点依然不成立
because an absence of deliberate emissions
因为缺乏有意的信号发射
does not preclude the detection of unintentional ones,
并不能排除被探测到无意信号的可能性
even if it's a lot less likely.
即便这种可能性要小得多
So the SETI Paradox isn't much of a paradox at all.
因此，SETI 悖论根本算不上什么悖论
It makes perfect sense to keep listening even if we never send another message.
即使我们再也不发送任何信息，继续监听也是完全合理的
But this is just a hypothetical, of course, because we
但这当然只是一种假设
probably will send more messages in the future.
因为我们未来很可能还会发送更多信息
After all, a planetwide ban would be extremely difficult to enforce,
毕竟，一项全球范围的禁令是很难执行的
which is why some critics seek not to keep quiet but to regulate the noise.
正因如此，一些批评者寻求的不是彻底不发，而是对这种“噪音”进行监管
While there's no consensus on what form such regulation should take,
虽然对于此类监管应采取何种形式尚无共识
popular ideas include an international treaty or policy
但一些流行的想法包括一项
that places restrictions on METI,
对 METI 施加限制的国际条约或政策
some sort of review board or oversight committee
让某个由选举产生的审查委员会或监督小组
elected to make decisions on humanity's behalf,
来代表人类做出决定？
or a democratic process where
或是一种民主程序
presumably everyone in the world gets a vote?
让全球每个人都能参与投票？
The logistics of which I don't even dare to think about.
至于其后勤操作的复杂性，我甚至不敢去想象
While different policies and regulations could go a long way
尽管不同的政策和法规可以在很大程度
to reduce the number of transmissions,
减少信息传输的数量
they're unlikely to eliminate the practice entirely.
但它们不太可能彻底杜绝这种行为
If people want to do something badly enough,
如果人们非常想做某件事
there will always be a way to do it.
总有办法能做
Outlaw METI in one country, and people will go to another.
在一个国家禁止 METI，人们就会跑到另一个国家进行
Make it illegal around the world, and people will do it in secret.
在全球范围内将其定为非法，人们就会秘密地进行
Hell, I wouldn't be surprised if a few messages
我去，如果已经有人偷偷发送了几条信息
have been dispatched in secret already.
我也不会感到惊讶
Think about it.
仔细想想看
Radio telescopes have been around for well over half a century.
射电望远镜已经存在了超过五十年
You're telling me not a single person has had the means and motive
你是在告诉我，竟然没有一个人有能力和动机
to beam a quick text to Proxima Centauri when no one else was looking?
在没人注意的时候，朝比邻星发一条简短的信息？
I'm not saying it's common, of course, but...
我当然不是说这很常见，但是...
...not once?
...一次都没有吗？
I don't know about that.
我不敢确定
As pointed out by evolutionary biologist Wallace Arthur,
正如进化生物学家华莱士·亚瑟所指出的那样
we are, for better or worse, a species that cannot stand not knowing.
无论好坏，我们都是一个无法忍受无知的物种
Whether it's the other side of a mountain,
无论是山的另一边
the other side of an ocean,
海洋的彼岸
or the other side of the galaxy,
还是银河系的另一端
the unknown will always evoke fear in some,
未知总会让一些人感到恐惧
and irresistible curiosity in others.
而让另一些人产生无法抗拒的好奇心
No amount of debating is going to change that.
再多的争论也无法改变这一点
Now, fortunately for those of you in camp fear,
现在，对于那些持担忧态度的人来说幸运的是，
METI is extraordinarily unlikely to succeed.
METI 几乎不可能成功
The stars we've targeted so far only account for a tiny fraction
我们迄今为止所瞄准的恒星
of the hundreds of billions of stars in the galaxy.
只占银河系数千亿颗恒星中的极小一部分
Most of which are within just a few tens of lightyears of Earth
它们中大多数距离地球仅几十光年
even though the galaxy is about 100 000 lightyears across.
尽管银河系的直径约为十万光年
For one of our messages to be received,
要让我们的某条信息被接收到，
the Milky Way is either so jam-packed with communicative civilizations
银河系中要么挤满了一堆善于交流的文明
that it's basically impossible to miss,
以至于几乎不可能忽略掉彼此
or we would need to be luckier than the combined luck
要么我们就必须比有史以来所有人类
of all humans who have ever lucked...
所拥有的运气总和还要幸运...
...and then some.
...甚至更甚
It's still fun to think about, of course,
当然，思考这些仍然很好玩
in the same way it's fun to think about other improbabilities like
就像思考其他不太可能的事情一样
winning the lottery.
比如中彩票
It could happen,
有可能发生
but it's probably not going to.
但发生不太可能
So, in my view, it doesn't really matter either way.
所以在我看来，无论哪种情况其实都无所谓
But if I had to pick a side,
但如果非要我选一边
I think I'm more persuaded by the arguments against METI than those in favor.
我觉得反对 METI 的论点比支持的更有说服力
As much as I would like to have confirmation that we're not alone,
尽管我非常希望有朝一日能确认我们并不孤单
tying one end of a rope around your waist
但把全人类系上绳子
and the other end around humanity
另一端系在自己的腰上
before sprinting headfirst into a dark room
然后一头冲进一间漆黑的房间
hoping there isn't a hole in the floor
只盼着地板上没有窟窿
is probably not the wisest approach.
这恐怕不是最明智的做法
Thank you for watching.
感谢观看